<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><masks><type> countriesCanada
        <name>_________Canada___________________________ </name>
        <Translation>____________Canada___________________________</Translation>
        <Aliases> Aiases: n/a </Aliases>
        <Date> Date for Masks: 1930's - 1980's </Date>
        <Frequency> Frequency: Uncommon </Frequency>
        <Country>Capital: Ottawa </Country>
        <Function>Use: Military/Civilian </Function>
        <Refrence>Refrence: CA-???</Refrence>
        <Ref> CA </Ref>
        <pic>../Images/flagCanada.jpg</pic>
        <price>Currency: Canadian Dollar</price>
        <Notes>Notes:  Because Britain still maintained control of Canada's foreign affairs under the Confederation Act, its declaration of war in 1914 automatically brought Canada into World War I. Volunteers sent to the Western Front later became part of the Canadian Corps. The Corps played a substantial role in the Battle of Vimy Ridge and other major battles of the war. Out of approximately 625,000 who served, about 60,000 were killed and another 173,000 were wounded. The Conscription Crisis of 1917 erupted when conservative Prime Minister Robert Borden brought in compulsory military service over the objection of French-speaking Quebecers. In 1919, Canada joined the League of Nations independently of Britain and, in 1931, the Statute of Westminster affirmed Canada's independence.Canada declared war on Germany independently during World War II under Liberal Prime Minister William Lyon Mackenzie King, three days after Britain. The first Canadian Army units arrived in Britain in December 1939. Canadian troops played important roles in the failed 1942 Dieppe Raid in France, the Allied invasion of Italy, the Normandy landings, the Battle of Normandy, and the Battle of the Scheldt in 1944. Canada provided asylum and protection for the monarchy of the Netherlands while that country was occupied, and is credited by the country for leadership and major contribution to its liberation from Nazi Germany.</Notes>
    </type>

<type> Civilian Respirator
    <name>Civilian Respirator</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s/1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Common</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Canada</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: CA-001</Refrence>
    <Ref>CA-001</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/CA-001.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $25
</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  During WWII, the Canadian military was mostly equipped with British Mark IV and V respirators and British Light Anti-Gas Respirators of various types. However, there were some Canadian masks that were only used in Canada, but were still derived directly from British designs. The Canadian Civilian Respirator is one of these masks. Its design is for the most part identical to the British General Civilian Respirator, however the Canadian version was made from a khaki material instead of black rubber. The Canadian version was even stored in a similar cardboard box like the British version. Canadian WWII Civilian Respirators are quite common, and can usually be found in mint, unissued condition for reasonable prices.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Baby's Anti-Gas Helmet
    <name>Baby's Anti-Gas Helmet</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  Infant Carrier</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. late 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Canada</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: CA-002</Refrence>
    <Ref>CA-002</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/CA-002.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price: $300</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  (UK Verison is Pictured below. The Canadian version would be Brown Instead of Black and Green.) Another WWII Canadian design derived directly from the British was used for a Baby's Anti-Gas Helmet produced for what seems to be exclusive issuance in Canada. The Canadian Helmet is very similar at a glance, but there are many notable differences. The first being the obvious color difference; British Baby's Anti-Gas Helmets were made of black and green materials, while the Canadian types were made of mostly brown materials. Another obvious difference can be seen in the shape of the window. British Infant Carriers used a more oval shaped pane, while the Canadian version used more of a rectangular shape. The Canadian version also used a rounded metal wire frame as opposed to a flattened metal frame. Another significant difference is the shape of the bellows. It might also be noted that the Canadian version seems to be quite rare, which the British types were made in large numbers and are fairly easy to find today in excellent condition.</Notes>
</type>


<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1940s/1950s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Canada</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: CA-003</Refrence>
    <Ref>CA-003</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/CA-003.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $60
</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This strange civilian mask is very similar to the US M16 Civilian Gas Mask in design, but was issued primarily in Canada. The mask's face piece was made from simple sheet rubber sealed at the chin. A 40mm filter canister was attached to the bottom of the mask and a rubber exhale valve was positioned on the front of the mask, just below the single clear plastic window. A six strap elastic head harness was used for suspension. This mask is somewhat rare today, but when found is usually in good condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> C3
    <name>C3</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1960s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Common</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Canada</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: CA-004</Refrence>
    <Ref>CA-004</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/CA-004.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price: $30 </price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Canadian C3 was basically Canada's updated version of the British Light Anti-Gas Respirator. Early versions of the Canadian C3 used a 60mm threaded filter canister which was mounted on the cheek of the face piece. The C3 remained in service for several years and was later updated with a filter inlet coupler that allowed 40mm threaded canisters to be used to conform with NATO standards. Canadian C3s are still very easy to find on the surplus market and are typically inexpensive.</Notes>
</type>

<type> C3
    <name>C3</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1960s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Common</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Canada</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: CA-005</Refrence>
    <Ref>CA-005</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/CA-005.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price: $50</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This later version of the Canadian C3 features a modified filter inlet assembly which used a 60mm to 40mm coupler, allowing for the use of 40mm threaded filter canisters, conforming with NATO standards. This version of the C3 is also quite common and can be easily found in excellent condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> C3 (export model)
    <name>C3 (export model)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  GTR75, M3 (Dutch designation)</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1960s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency: Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Holland (The Netherlands)</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: CA-006</Refrence>
    <Ref>CA-006</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/CA-006.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $80
</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This version of the Canadian C3 was modified and manufactured for export to Holland for use by their armed forces. The face piece mold for this version was slightly different and the mask came equipped with a threaded plastic screen which could be attached to the front of the mask. This version of the C3 is somewhat rare and difficult to find today.</Notes>
</type>

<type> C4 (Black Version)
    <name>C4 (Black Version)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1980s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Common</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Canada</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: CA-007</Refrence>
    <Ref>CA-007</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/CA-007.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $160</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Canadian C4 is Canada's modern NBC defense respirator developed by DREO (Defense Research Establishment Ottawa). It is very comfortable and offers a wide field of view as well as the ability to attach the filter canister to either the left or right side of the face piece. The C4 also utilizes modern technological advances incorporating a drinking system and a highly effective voice-mitter. An adjustable head-net made of a mesh type material is used for suspension, keeping pace with other similar modern NBC masks from other countries. The C4 was made in both black and green, black being the more common setup.</Notes>
</type>

<type> C4 (Green Version)
    <name>C4 (Green Version)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1980s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Common</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Canada</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: CA-008</Refrence>
    <Ref>CA-008</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/CA-008.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $160</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Canadian C4 is Canada's modern NBC defense respirator developed by DREO (Defense Research Establishment Ottawa). It is very comfortable and offers a wide field of view as well as the ability to attach the filter canister to either the left or right side of the face piece. The C4 also utilizes modern technological advances incorporating a drinking system and a highly effective voice-mitter. An adjustable head-net made of a mesh type material is used for suspension, keeping pace with other similar modern NBC masks from other countries. The C4 was made in both black and green, black being the more common setup.</Notes>
</type>             </masks>