<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
 <?xml-stylesheet href="PageLayout.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?> <masks>
<type> countriesImperalRussia
        <name>Imperial Russia </name>
        <Translation>The Russian Empire</Translation>
        <Aliases>  Tzarist Russia</Aliases>
        <Date> Date for Masks: 1916 </Date>
        <Frequency>  Scarce </Frequency>
        <Country>Capital: St. Petersburg </Country>
        <Function> Military </Function>
        <Refrence> RU-???</Refrence>
        <Ref> RU </Ref>
        <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/flagImperialRussia.jpg</pic>
        <price>Currency: Soviet ruble</price>
        <Notes> Tsar Nicholas II and his subjects entered World War I with enthusiasm and patriotism, with the defence of Russia's fellow Orthodox Slavs, the Serbs, as the main battle cry. In August 1914, the Russian army entered Germany to support the French armies. Military reversals and shortages among the civilian population, soon soured much of the population. German control of the Baltic Sea and German-Ottoman control of the Black Sea severed Russia from most of its foreign supplies and potential markets. By the middle of 1915 the impact of the war was demoralizing. Food and fuel were in short supply, casualties were increasing, and inflation was mounting. Strikes increased among low-paid factory workers, and there were reports that peasants, who wanted land reforms, were restless. Nicholas II directed the war effort personally, leaving the Tsarina, Alexandra, to act as regent at home. Alexandra was influenced by a semiliterate mystic, Grigory Rasputin. Rasputin's assassination in late 1916 by a clique of nobles ended the scandal but did not restore the autocracy's lost prestige. On March 3, 1917, a strike was organized on a factory in the capital Saint Petersburg; within a week nearly all the workers in the city were idle, and street fighting broke out. When the tsar dismissed the Duma and ordered strikers to return to work, his orders triggered the February Revolution. The Duma refused to disband, the strikers held mass meetings in defiance of the regime, and the army openly sided with the workers. A few days later a provisional government headed by Georgy Lvov was named by the Duma. Meanwhile, the socialists in Saint Petersburg had formed a Soviet (council) of workers and soldier's deputies, forming an uneasy alliance with the Provisional Government. With his authority destroyed, Nicholas abdicated on 2 March 1917 (Julian Calendar; the Gregorian date was 15 March). He and his family were subsequently murdered by Bolsheviks during the Russian Civil War. </Notes>
    </type>
    
<type> Зелинский-Кумант
    <name>Зелинский-Кумант</name>
    <Translation> Zelinsky-Kumant</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1916</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Russia</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> RU-001</Refrence>
    <Ref>RU-001</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/RU-001.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $200+</price>
    <Notes>  Sometime during 1916, an engineer by the name of A. Kumant and a Russian chemist named Nikolai Zelinsky developed what came to be known as the Zelinsky-Kumant gas mask. This was the start of a long trend of Russian 'helmet' type gas masks. The Zelinsky-Kumant consisted of a mask of thick rubber that encapsulated the wearers entire head, thus eliminating the need for a head harness. The protrusion from the nose area of the mask was typically turned inside out (and into the mask) which allowed the wearer to insert a finger and wipe the eye pieces clear when they fogged up. Another unique feature of the Zelinsky-Kumant design, was that the mask itself could be folded and stored inside a metal lid that fit snugly on top of the filter. This made the entire unit quite easy to carry and stow when not in use. There were at least two or three variations of the Zelinsky-Kumant made during the WWI era and all are most certainly difficult masks to find today. Most were either disposed of or destroyed over the years. The example pictured is in excellent preserved condition for its age.</Notes>
</type>             </masks>