<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
 <?xml-stylesheet href="PageLayout.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?> <masks>
<type> countriesJapan
        <name>Japan </name>
        <Translation>Nippon</Translation>
        <Aliases>  n/a</Aliases>
        <Date> Date for Masks: 1930 - 1960s </Date>
        <Frequency>  Rare </Frequency>
        <Country>Capital: Tokyo </Country>
        <Function> Military/Civilian/Industrial </Function>
        <Refrence> JA-???</Refrence>
        <Ref> JA </Ref>
        <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/flagJapan.jpg</pic>
        <price>Currency: Yen</price>
        <Notes> World War I enabled Japan, which joined the side of the victorious Allies, to widen its influence and territorial holdings. It continued its expansionist policy by occupying Manchuria in 1931; as a result of international condemnation of this occupation, Japan resigned from the League of Nations two years later. In 1936, Japan signed the Anti-Comintern Pact with Nazi Germany, and the 1940 Tripartite Pact made it one of the Axis Powers. In 1941, Japan negotiated the Soviet–Japanese Neutrality Pact. The Empire of Japan invaded other parts of China in 1937, precipitating the Second Sino-Japanese War (1937–1945). In 1940, the Empire then invaded French Indochina, after which the United States placed an oil embargo on Japan. On December 7, 1941, Japan attacked the US naval base at Pearl Harbor and declared war, bringing the US into World War II. After the Soviet invasion of Manchuria and the atomic bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki in 1945, Japan agreed to an unconditional surrender on August 15. The war cost Japan and the rest of the Greater East Asia Co-Prosperity Sphere millions of lives and left much of the nation's industry and infrastructure destroyed. The Allies (led by the US) repatriated millions of ethnic Japanese from colonies and military camps throughout Asia, largely eliminating the Japanese empire and restoring the independence of its conquered territories. The Allies also convened the International Military Tribunal for the Far East on May 3, 1946 to prosecute some Japanese leaders for war crimes. However, the bacteriological research units and members of the imperial family involved in the war were exonerated from criminal prosecutions by the Supreme Allied Commander despite calls for trials for both groups.
        </Notes>
    </type>
    
<type> Army Gas Mask, Type 87
    <name>Army Gas Mask, Type 87</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1934</Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-001</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-001</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-001.jpg</pic>
    <price> $100</price>
    <Notes>  The Type 87 is an early Japanese Army gas mask that is very similar to the US A.T. gas mask, with internal Tissot type tubes in place to help reduce fogging of the glass eye pieces. The face piece was made from a rubberized fabric with a single opening in the chin area for the inlet/outlet assembly.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown  
    <name>Unknown  </name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-022</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-022</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-022.jpg</pic>
    <price> $100</price>
    <Notes>  This early Japanese gas mask was most likely used by both the military and civil defense personnel. The mask was made from a rubberized fabric materiel. These types of Japanese masks are quite rare, and are prone to rapid deterioration when exposed to harsh temperatures.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Type 1/Model A
    <name>Type 1/Model A</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Civil Defense/Military</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-002</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-002</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-002.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $135</price>
    <Notes>  This early Japanese mask from W.W.II was most likely used for civilian duty but also may have been issued to the Japanese army. It is different from the later Model 99 in that it has a fabric covered rubber face piece instead of the usual tan rubber face piece. The Type 1/Model A was also issued with a corrugated rubber breathing tube with an attached filter instead of the filter attached directly to the face piece.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Model 99
    <name>Model 99</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Civil Defense/Military</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-003</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-003</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-003.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $150</price>
    <Notes>  The Japanese Army Model 99 gas mask is definitely the most commonly found Japanese gas mask from W.W.II. It features a soft tan rubber face piece and an elastic/fabric head harness. A variation of the Model 99 was also issued with a corrugated rubber breathing tube and large filter (below).</Notes>
</type>

<type> Model 99
    <name>Model 99</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Civil Defense/Military</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-004</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-004</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-004.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $125</price>
    <Notes>  The Japanese Army Model 99 gas mask is definitely the most commonly found Japanese gas mask from W.W.II. It features a soft tan rubber face piece and an elastic/fabric head harness. A variation of the Model 99 was also issued with the filter attached directly to the face piece (above). The Model 99 is most likely a civilian mask but it may have been used by the military as well.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-005</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-005</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-005.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $200+ </price>
    <Notes>  This rare Japanese mask was most likely used by civilians for industrial applications. It is very close in appearance to other Japanese civilian duty gas masks from the W.W.II era. However, this mask was made of a black rubber instead of the typical orange or tan rubber which was used on other more common gas masks during this period. In addition, the head harness configuration is also unlike other Japanese W.W.II era masks.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Civilian Gas Mask, Type 2A, Modification D
    <name>Civilian Gas Mask, Type 2A, Modification D</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c . 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Civil Defense</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-006</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-006</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-006.jpg</pic>
    <price> $150  </price>
    <Notes>  During W.W.II, the Japanese made several different types of gas masks for civilians and civil defense. This mask, came in two versions</Notes>
</type>

<type> Civilian Gas Mask, Type 2A, Modification D
    <name>Civilian Gas Mask, Type 2A, Modification D</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c . 1942</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Civil Defense</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-007</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-007</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-007.jpg</pic>
    <price> $165   </price>
    <Notes>  During W.W.II, the Japanese made several different types of gas masks for civilians and civil defense. This mask, came in two versions</Notes>
</type>

<type> Civilian Gas Mask, Type 2, Modification C
    <name>Civilian Gas Mask, Type 2, Modification C</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Civil Defense</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-008</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-008</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-008.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $375</price>
    <Notes>  This Japanese mask is most likely another type of W.W.II civil defense mask. It may have also been issued with a filter attached directly to the face piece. This mask is quite difficult to find today on the collector's market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   FMC Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s/1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian (Children)</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-009</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-009</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-009.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $280</price>
    <Notes>  This small WWII era Japanese mask was most likely designed for children. It was made of a light-weight rubber material and used a smaller than normal filter canister. The mask was carried in a small canvas bag.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Gas Mask, Navy Type, Model Unknown
    <name>Gas Mask, Navy Type, Model Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-010</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-010</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-010.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $300+</price>
    <Notes>  The W.W.II Japanese Imperial Navy gas mask is one of the most sought after Japanese war time items today. Most of these masks perished at the bottom of the Pacific, making them quite scarce in any condition. This version is unlike the other more common versions in that the eye pieces were shaped differently, it used a different elastic head harness and the speech diaphragm surface is slightly different than the typical type. These masks were typically carried in a large case, which housed the entire unit and sometimes extra supplies.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Gas Mask, Navy Type, Model Unknown
    <name>Gas Mask, Navy Type, Model Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-011</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-011</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-011.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $200+</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the Japanese Navy mask is very similar to the above version, however this type was equipped with a rather large speech diaphragm and an exhale valve off to the side. This type was most likely designed for use by officers who needed to give commands and communicate on a frequent basis.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Gas Mask, Navy Type, Model Unknown
    <name>Gas Mask, Navy Type, Model Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-012</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-012</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-012.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $200+</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the Navy Mask is again very similar to the above versions, but was made with a Bakelite exhale valve. It is possible that this mask was also carried by the Japanese infantry as well.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Gas Mask, Navy Type, Model Unknown
    <name>Gas Mask, Navy Type, Model Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-013</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-013</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-013.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $200+</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the Navy Mask is almost identical to the above version, but used a metal exhale valve guard as opposed to the Bakelite. These changes may have been a result of supply shortages and/or modifications designed to make the mask lighter.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Gas Mask, Navy Type, Model Unknown
    <name>Gas Mask, Navy Type, Model Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-014</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-014</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-014.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $325</price>
    <Notes>  This Japanese W.W.II era mask is very similar to the above Navy versions. It may have been used as a Navy mask or possibly as a standard combat mask for infantry. For the most part, the mask is identical to the above version with the Bakelite exhale valve, however, this mask used a black rubber face piece and a black rubber breathing tube. These black rubber versions seem to be even more scarce than the fabric types.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Gas Mask, Navy Type, Model Unknown
    <name>Gas Mask, Navy Type, Model Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-015</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-015</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-015.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $200+</price>
    <Notes>  This Japanese W.W.II era mask is very similar to the above Navy versions. It may have been used as a Navy mask or possibly as a standard combat mask for infantry. For the most part, the mask is identical to the above version with the metal exhale valve, however, this mask used a black rubber face piece and a black rubber breathing tube. These black rubber versions seem to be even more scarce than the fabric types.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Air Defense Gas Mask, Type 16th Year, Model A
    <name>Air Defense Gas Mask, Type 16th Year, Model A</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-016</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-016</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-016.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $95</price>
    <Notes>  During W.W.II, several similarly styled civilian gas masks were manufactured in Japan. The earliest of these types was made of a thick canvas type material as opposed to rubber which was used for later versions. The mask had a head harness made of wide fabric straps which were adjustable around the chin area on each side. It featured a single plastic eye shied and a small fixed filter cartridge on the front of the face piece. This configuration was used on at least two other Japanese civilian gas masks from the W.W.II era.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Air Defense Gas Mask, Type 17th Year, Model A
    <name>Air Defense Gas Mask, Type 17th Year, Model A</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1920s/1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-017</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-017</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-017.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $80</price>
    <Notes>  During W.W.II, several closely styled civilian gas masks were manufactured in Japan. This type is definitely the most common. It is similar to the earlier fabric type but it was manufactured with a dark green rubber face piece and head harness. The visor and fixed filter canister remained the same.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Air Defense Gas Mask, Type 17th Year, Model B
    <name>Air Defense Gas Mask, Type 17th Year, Model B</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1920s/1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-018</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-018</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-018.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $75+</price>
    <Notes>  During W.W.II, several similarly styled civilian gas masks were manufactured in Japan. This type was most likely manufactured toward the end of the war when Japan was most concerned about Allied air raids. This mask is basically the same as the earlier green type but was made of a darker rubber with an exhale valve integrated into the left side of the face piece. This model is quite a bit more scarce than the earlier types as it was probably manufactured in smaller numbers.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Koken Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s/1960s</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Japan</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> JA-019</Refrence>
    <Ref>JA-019</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/JA-019.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $100+</price>
    <Notes>  This post war Japanese mask was most likely used for civilian purposes, but may have also been used for industrial applications. It was made of a thick green rubber and came with a small filter canister that attached in the chin position. Both the mask and filter are marked 'Koken', the company of manufacture.</Notes>
</type>        </masks>