<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
 <?xml-stylesheet href="PageLayout.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?> <masks>

<type> countriesModRus
        <name>Modern Russia </name>
        <Translation>The Russian Federation</Translation>
        <Aliases>  Russia</Aliases>
        <Date> Date for Masks: 1922 - Current </Date>
        <Frequency>  Uncommon </Frequency>
        <Country>Capital: Moscow </Country>
        <Function> Military/Civilian </Function>
        <Refrence> RU-???</Refrence>
        <Ref> RU </Ref>
        <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/flagRussia.jpg</pic>
        <price>Currency Russian Rubles</price>
            <Notes> With the dissolution of the Soviet Union on 25 December 1991, the Russian Federation became an independent country. Russia was the largest of the fifteen republics that made up the Soviet Union, accounting for over 60% of the GDP and over 50% of the Soviet population. Russians also dominated the Soviet military and the Communist Party. Thus, Russia was widely accepted as the Soviet Union's successor state in diplomatic affairs and it assumed the USSR's permanent membership and veto in the UN Security Council. Despite this acceptance, post-Soviet Russia lacked the military and political power of the former USSR. Russia managed to make the other ex-Soviet republics voluntarily disarm themselves of nuclear weapons and concentrated them under the command of the still effective rocket and space forces, but for the most part the Russian army and fleet were in near disarray by 1992. Prior to the dissolution of the Soviet Union, Boris Yeltsin had been elected President of Russia in June 1991 in the first direct presidential election in Russian history. In October 1991, as Russia was on the verge of independence, Yeltsin announced that Russia would proceed with radical market-oriented reform. 
Modern Russian Masks are generally military and are uncommon on the market like most modern masks.
        </Notes>
    </type>

<type> Противогаз ГП-7
    <name>Противогаз ГП-7</name>
    <Translation> Gas Mask GP-7</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1980s</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Russia </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> RU-045</Refrence>
    <Ref>RU-045</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/RU-045.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $40 </price>
    <Notes>  The GP-7 was designed to replace the earlier GP-5 civilian mask, finally getting away from the uncomfortable "helmet style" mask that was used for several decades. The mask was molded of a thick black rubber that had an inner collar around the edges to help create a better face seal. The GP-7 was later updated to include a drinking mechanism. The GP-7 is now fairly common on the surplus market and can be found in new condition with all the proper accessories.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Противогаз ГП-7В
    <name>Противогаз ГП-7В</name>
    <Translation> Gas Mask GP-7V</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. late 1980s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Russia
</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> RU-046</Refrence>
    <Ref>RU-046</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/RU-046.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $50 </price>
    <Notes>  The GP-7V is an updated version of the GP-7 (above) that integrated a drinking mechanism which could be attached to a canteen. Overall, the mask's shape and fit did not change much from the earlier GP-7. The GP-7V does however seem to be a bit harder to find on the surplus market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Противогаз ПМК
    <name>Противогаз ПМК</name>
    <Translation> Gas Mask PMK</Translation>
    <Aliases>   LMK</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. late 1980s - early 1990s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Russia
</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> RU-047</Refrence>
    <Ref>RU-047</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/RU-047.jpg</pic>
    <price> $25</price>
    <Notes>  The PMK was designed to be the modern NBC respirator for use by the military, completely getting away from the long used "helmet style" gas masks. The mask was made of thick black rubber, like the GP-7 and used and drinking mechanism like the GP-7V. The original version of the PMK was later updated using unpainted metal parts (see below). This version of the PMK seems to be more difficult to find that the updated type.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Противогаз ПМК (Updated Model)
    <name>Противогаз ПМК (Updated Model)</name>
    <Translation> Gas Mask PMK</Translation>
    <Aliases>   LMK</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. early 1990s</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Russia </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> RU-048</Refrence>
    <Ref>RU-048</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/RU-048.jpg</pic>
    <price> $30</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the PMK is basically identical to the previous version, but it used unpainted metal parts. The shape of the face piece may also vary slightly from the previous version. This version also seems to be more common on the surplus market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Противогаз ГП-7ВМ / Противогаз ПМК-2
    <name>Противогаз ГП-7ВМ / Противогаз ПМК-2</name>
    <Translation> Gas Mask GP-7VM / Gas Mask PMK-2</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1990s</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Russia </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> RU-049</Refrence>
    <Ref>RU-049</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/RU-049.jpg</pic>
    <price> $180</price>
    <Notes>  This mask, designated the GP-7VM for civilian use, and the PMK-2 for military use, was basically an updated version of the PMK. The filter canister could be attached to either side, alleviating the need to manufacture masks for left handed and right handed use. The masks face seal was also slightly improved, but overall the shape and fit of the mask remained unchanged.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Противогаз Детский Фильтрующий ПДФ-2Д
    <name>Противогаз Детский Фильтрующий ПДФ-2Д</name>
    <Translation> Children's Filtering Gas Mask PDF-2D</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1980s/1990s</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Russia </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> RU-053</Refrence>
    <Ref>RU-053</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/RU-053.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $180</price>
    <Notes>  The Russian PDF-2D is an updated version of the earlier children's masks used during the Soviet era. The PDF-2D was designed for use by children from ages 1-5 years old. The mask used a black face piece designated the МД-4, and was equipped with a ГП-7к filter canister.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Изолирующий Противогаз ИП-4М
    <name>Изолирующий Противогаз ИП-4М</name>
    <Translation> Insulator Gas Mask IP-4M</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. mid 1980s-early 1990s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Russia </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> RU-050</Refrence>
    <Ref>RU-050</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/RU-050.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $195</price>
    <Notes>  The IP-4M is a closed circuit re-breather that could be used in areas where the oxygen level is to low to sustain life. The device worked by rapidly inflating an air bladder with oxygen generated by a chemical reaction in the РП-4 (RP-4) regenerating canister. The bladder was housed inside the masks carrier below the regenerating canister and carried here while in use and not in use. The face piece used with the IP-4M unit is identical to the one used with the IP-6, but was manufactured with black rubber instead of gray.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Изолирующий Противогаз ИП-6
    <name>Изолирующий Противогаз ИП-6</name>
    <Translation> Insulator Gas Mask IP-6</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. mid 1980s-early 1990s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Russia </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> RU-051</Refrence>
    <Ref>RU-051</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/RU-051.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $180</price>
    <Notes>  The IP-6 is a larger closed circuit re-breather unit that could used in areas where the oxygen level is to low to sustain life. The device worked by rapidly inflating a large bladder with oxygen generated by a chemical reaction in the РП-6 (RP-6) regenerating canister. The bladder was worn around the neck while in use and stored in the carrier while not in use. The face piece used with the IP-6 re-breather unit is identical to the one used with the IP-4M, but was manufactured with gray rubber instead of black. The IP-6 can be found on the surplus market in complete un-issued condition with all of the proper accessories and manual.</Notes>
</type>

<type> PLF
    <name>PLF</name>
    <Translation> n/a</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1990s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Russia </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> RU-052</Refrence>
    <Ref>RU-052</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/RU-052.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $145</price>
    <Notes>  The PLF gas mask is most likely for use by air crew and/or tank crew. The mask uses a one piece visor creating a wide field of view, a design not typical for Russian masks. The PLF is also equipped with a microphone attachment for use with standard Russian communications equipment. The PLF is fairly new, and somewhat difficult to find on the surplus market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> n/a</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 2001 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Russia </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> RU-087</Refrence>
    <Ref>RU-087</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/RU-087.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $150+</price>
    <Notes>  This modern Russian mask is very similar to several other "panorama" styled masks made by various countries. The mask features a single, clear visor for maximum visibility and an inner mask to prevent fogging. The mask accepts standard 40mm thread filter canisters and came with a olive drab carrying po uc h.</Notes>
</type>
</masks>