<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
 <?xml-stylesheet href="PageLayout.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?> <masks>
<type> countriesNetherlands
        <name>Netherlands </name>
        <Translation>Holland</Translation>
        <Aliases>  n/a</Aliases>
        <Date> Date for Masks: 1933 - 1980s </Date>
        <Frequency>  Uncommon/Rare </Frequency>
        <Country>Capital: Amsterdam </Country>
        <Function> Military/Civilian </Function>
        <Refrence> NE-???</Refrence>
        <Ref> NE </Ref>
        <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/flagNetherlands.jpg</pic>
        <price>Currency: Euro</price>
        <Notes> Although the Netherlands remained neutral during World War I, it was heavily involved in the war. German general Count Schlieffen, who was Chief of the Imperial German General Staff had originally planned to invade the Netherlands while advancing into France in the original Schlieffen Plan. This was changed by Schlieffen's successor Helmuth von Moltke the Younger in order to maintain Dutch neutrality. Later during the war Dutch neutrality proved essential to German survival until the blockade by Great Britain in 1916, when the import of goods through the Netherlands was no longer possible. However, the Dutch were able to continue to remain neutral during the war using their diplomacy and their ability to trade.The Netherlands intended to remain neutral during the Second World War, although contingency plans involving the armies of Belgium, France and the United Kingdom were drawn up in case of German aggression. Despite this neutrality, Nazi Germany invaded the Netherlands on 10 May 1940 as part of their campaign against the Allied forces. French forces in the south and British ships in the west came to help but turned around quickly, evacuating many civilians and several thousand German prisoners of war from the German elite airborne divisions. The country was overrun in five days. Only after (but not because of) the bombing of Rotterdam, the main element of the Dutch army surrendered on 14 May 1940; although a Dutch and French force held the western part of Zeeland for some time after the surrender. The Kingdom as such, continued the war from the colonial empire; the government in exile resided in London.</Notes>
    </type>
    
<type> Model F
    <name>Model F</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1933</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  The Netherlands</Country>
    <Function>  Military (Mounted)</Function>
    <Refrence> NE-001</Refrence>
    <Ref>NE-001</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/NE-001.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $200+</price>
    <Notes>  The Dutch Model F is definitely a uniquely designed mask that was used for troops on horseback. The face piece was secured via a five point head harness that was attached to a rubber ring around the front of the mask. This method of suspension helped support the weight of the cumbersome breathing tube and filter. Another unique feature is the 'flapper' type exhale valve which was housed inside a metal case fixed in the middle of the breathing tube. The Dutch Model F is quite scarce today and when found it is usually in poor condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Model G
    <name>Model G</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   AR Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1937</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  The Netherlands</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> NE-002</Refrence>
    <Ref>NE-002</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/NE-002.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $200+</price>
    <Notes>  Like the Model F, the Model G is quite unique. Similarly, the Model G used an elastic head harness which was adjusted at five points around a rubber ring that was attached to the front of the face piece. This setup helped support the weight of the heavy hose and filter. The Model G mask is quite rare and is somewhat difficult to find in good condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Veritex
    <name>Veritex</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Veritex Gasmasker</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1939</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  The Netherlands</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> NE-003</Refrence>
    <Ref>NE-003</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/NE-003.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $200</price>
    <Notes>  The Veritex Gas Mask is a civilian protective mask with characteristics similar to several other WWII civilian respirators. Like the German VM44, the Veritex uses a full "helmet" type face piece that covers the whole head and ears. There is also an exhale valve present as part of the inlet assembly. The Veritex mask is made from a thin green rubber material that is prone to dry rot, and thus, few examples survive today in good condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Duiker-Vredestein Volksgasmasker
    <name>Duiker-Vredestein Volksgasmasker</name>
    <Translation> Duiker-Vredestein Peoples Gas Mask </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1938</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  The Netherlands</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> NE-004</Refrence>
    <Ref>NE-004</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/NE-004.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $85</price>
    <Notes>  The Duiker-Vredestein Volksgasmasker was issued during W.W.II to civilian populations in the Netherlands. It was a simple mask with two thin plastic eye pieces and a flutter type exhale valve. The Duiker-Vredestein Volksgasmasker can be found on the collector's market in un-issued condition, but is getting harder to find. Another version of this mask was also made by Hevea.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. late 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  The Netherlands</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> NE-010</Refrence>
    <Ref>NE-010</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/NE-010.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $200</price>
    <Notes>  This rare civilian mask was manufactured by Hevea, and is very similar to the above mask. The mask has no exhale valve, and appears to be a very simply, and most likely cheaply constructed civilian mask. The mask was carried in a tall metal carrying canister.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Model K (Vredestein)
    <name>Model K (Vredestein)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   K53</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  The Netherlands</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> NE-005</Refrence>
    <Ref>NE-005</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/NE-005.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $40</price>
    <Notes>  The Dutch Model K is quite an interesting gas mask. The filter inlet was designed to accept both a 40 mm NATO thread filter canister or a 60 mm thread canister. This was accomplished by a dual threaded inlet assembly. The Model K was originally manufactured by Vredestein, however later an updated version was manufactured by Hevea (see below). The Model K can be found on the surplus market but is becoming more and more difficult to locate.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Model K (Hevea)
    <name>Model K (Hevea)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   K53</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s/60s</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  The Netherlands</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> NE-006</Refrence>
    <Ref>NE-006</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/NE-006.jpg</pic>
    <price> $70</price>
    <Notes>  Pictured to the right is the Dutch Model K manufactured by Hevea. Earlier versions were made by Vredestein (see above). However, both versions are for the most part identical. This newer version has a better elastic head harness and the rubber appears to be of a higher quality. The Model K can be found on the surplus market but is becoming more and more difficult to locate.</Notes>
</type>

<type> M3
    <name>M3</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   C3 (Canadian designation), GTR75</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1980s</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  The Netherlands</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> CA-006</Refrence>
    <Ref>CA-006</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/CA-006.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $ </price>
    <Notes>  The Dutch M3 is a licensed, exported version of the Canadian C3. The M3 uses a 60mm filter canister but can also be fitted with a 40mm adapter. The M3 can be easily distinguished from the Canadian C3 by the plastic guard on the front of the mask.</Notes>
</type>              </masks>