<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
 <?xml-stylesheet href="PageLayout.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?> <masks>
<type> countriesNorway
        <name>Norway </name>
        <Translation>Kingdom of Norway</Translation>
        <Aliases>  n/a </Aliases> 
        <Date>Date for Masks: 1940s - 1960s </Date>
        <Frequency>  Rare/Scarce </Frequency>
        <Country>Capital: Oslo </Country>
        <Function> Military/Civilian </Function>
        <Refrence> NO-???</Refrence>
        <Ref> NO </Ref>
        <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/flagNorway.jpg</pic>
        <price>Currency: krone</price>
            <Notes> During World War I, Norway was a neutral country. In reality, however, Norway had been pressured by the United Kingdom to hand over increasingly large parts of its massive merchant fleet to the UK at low rates, as well as to join the trade blockade against Germany. Norwegian merchant marine ships with Norwegian sailors were then required to sail under the British flag and risk being sunk by German submarines. Thus, many Norwegian sailors and ships were lost. 
Norway also proclaimed its neutrality during World War II, but Norway was invaded by German forces on 9 April 1940. Norway was unprepared for the German surprise attack, so military and naval resistance only lasted for two months. The armed forces in the north launched an offensive against the German forces in the Battles of Narvik, until they were forced to surrender on June 10 after losing British help following the Fall of France. During the five years of Nazi occupation, Norwegians built a resistance movement which fought the German occupation forces with both civil disobedience and armed resistance.    </Notes>
    </type>
    
<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country> Norway </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Civil Defense</Function>
    <Refrence> NO-001</Refrence>
    <Ref>NO-001</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/NO-001.jpg</pic>
    <price> $150</price>
    <Notes>  This WWII era Norwegian gas mask was most likely a civil defense mask. This one, was perhaps used for fire fighting, as red filter canisters typically represent. This mask was issued and carried in a tall metal canister.</Notes>
</type>

<type> LF/62
    <name>LF/62</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country> Norway </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> NO-002</Refrence>
    <Ref>NO-002</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/NO-002.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $115</price>
    <Notes>  This Norwegian gas mask is made of a gray rubber and fitted with a cheek mounted filter inlet. It is interesting because the clear plastic view finder extends down the side of the face piece opposite the filter, giving the wearer a much wider field of view.</Notes>
</type>

<type> IMA
    <name>IMA</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country> Norway </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> NO-003</Refrence>
    <Ref>NO-003</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/NO-003.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $120</price>
    <Notes>  This Norwegian mask is similar in many way to the above version, however this version was made of green rubber with a filter inlet in the snout position. Like the above version, this mask also used a clear plastic sheet for a visor, which extended down both sides of the face piece.</Notes>
</type>               </masks>