<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
 <?xml-stylesheet href="PageLayout.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?> <masks>
<type> countriesSpain
        <name>Spain </name>
        <Translation>Kingdom of Spain</Translation>
        <Aliases>  n/a </Aliases> 
        <Date>Date for Masks: 1940s - 1960s </Date>
        <Frequency>  Rare/Scarce </Frequency>
        <Country>Capital: Madrid </Country>
        <Function> Military/Civilian </Function>
        <Refrence> SP-???</Refrence>
        <Ref> SP </Ref>
        <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/flagSpain.jpg</pic>
        <price>Currency: Euro</price>
            <Notes> The Spanish Civil War,  the Nationalist forces, led by General Francisco Franco, emerged victorious with the support of Nazi Germany and Fascist Italy. Popular Front government side was supported by the Soviet Union and Mexico and International Brigades, including the American Abraham Lincoln Brigade, but it was not supported officially by the Western powers due to the British-led policy of Non-Intervention. The Civil War claimed the lives of over 500,000 people and caused the flight of up to a half-million citizens. The Spanish Civil War has been called the first battle of the Second World War; under Franco the country was neutral in the Second World War, although sympathetic to the Axis.In the Basque Country, moderate Basque nationalism has coexisted with a radical nationalist movement led by the armed organisation ETA. The group was formed in 1959 during Franco's rule but has continued to wage its violent campaign even after the restoration of democracy and the return of a large measure of regional autonomy. On 23 February 1981, rebel elements among the security forces seized the Cortes in an attempt to impose a military backed government. King Juan Carlos took personal command of the military and successfully ordered the coup plotters, via national television, to surrender.   </Notes>
</type>


<type> Máscara C.M.P.
    <name>Máscara C.M.P.</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Spain </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> SP-001</Refrence>
    <Ref>SP-001</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/SP-001.jpg</pic>
    <price> $125</price>
    <Notes>  The Spanish C.M.P. Gas Mask is an interesting respirator based on the German GM24 series gas mask. It used a tall metal filter canister and a long fabricized breathing hose attached to an angular metal inhale/exhale assembly. The C.M.P. is a very scarce mask today and when found is usually in poor hardened condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Draeger Blanco Gas Mask
    <name>Draeger Blanco Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Spain </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civil Defense</Function>
    <Refrence> SP-002</Refrence>
    <Ref>SP-002</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/SP-002.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $30</price>
    <Notes>  This Spanish gas mask from WWII is a licensed Draeger design most likely used for civil defense. There were several variants of this face piece design used in Spain for many similar masks. This early type used a rubber face piece with a disc shaped exhale valve on the left side of the mask.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Draeger Blanco Gas Mask
    <name>Draeger Blanco Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Spain </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civil Defense</Function>
    <Refrence> SP-003</Refrence>
    <Ref>SP-003</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/SP-003.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $30</price>
    <Notes>  This Spanish gas mask from WWII is very similar to the above version, however the materials for its production slightly vary. The filter canister this mask came with is also different and bears marking indicating it is a civil defense filter canister.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Draeger Blanco Gas Mask
    <name>Draeger Blanco Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Spain </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civil Defense</Function>
    <Refrence> SP-004</Refrence>
    <Ref>SP-004</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/SP-004.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $70 </price>
    <Notes>  This mask, also very similar to the above Draeger Blanco types, was also made of dark rubber and carried in a tall metal canister. However, this mask used a different design incorporating the inlet/outlet valves into one assembly at the chin of the mask.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Degea Gas Mask
    <name>Degea Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Spain </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civil Defense</Function>
    <Refrence> SP-005</Refrence>
    <Ref>SP-005</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/SP-005.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $95 </price>
    <Notes>  This mask, manufactured under the Auer license, is another Spanish mask from WWII based on German design. This mask may have been used for troops deployed to Africa, as the color of the mask and carrier reflect uniform colors for use in desert areas. However, this mask may just be another civilian defense mask used in Spain during the mid 1940s.</Notes>
</type>

<type> M2
    <name>M2</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1980s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Spain
</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> SP-006</Refrence>
    <Ref>SP-006</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/SP-006.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $65 </price>
    <Notes>  The Spanish M2 is a modern NBC respirator that closely resembles the German M65 series gas mask. The M2 most likely was modeled after this successful German design, like many other similar masks from other countries.</Notes>
</type>        </masks>