<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
 <?xml-stylesheet href="PageLayout.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?> <masks>
<type> countriesUSA
        <name>U.S.A </name>
        <Translation>The United States of America</Translation>
        <Aliases>  US, America</Aliases>
        <Date> Date for Masks: 1910 - Current </Date>
        <Frequency>  Common/Ucommon </Frequency>
        <Country>Capital: Washington D.C. </Country>
        <Function> Military/Civilian/Industrial </Function>
        <Refrence> US-???</Refrence>
        <Ref> US </Ref>
        <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/flagUSA.jpg</pic>
        <price>Currency: Dollar</price>    
        <Notes> The United States has a long history with gas masks dating back to the mid 1800's. American were essential inventing many of the earyl gas mask essentials. An early example is the gas mask was patented in 1849, Lewis Haslett. It was an "Inhaler or Lung Protector," issued for an air purifying respirator. Haslett's device filtered dust from the air. When the United States entered the World War I  the U.S. Army was unprepared for chemical warfare and had to use borrowed foreign equipment. Soldiers were issued a British Small Box Respirator  for the highest level of protection and a French M2 Mask for long-term wear comfort. Unfortunately, the untrained troops had a tendency to initially put on the S.B.R. following a gas attack and then switch to the M2 when it appeared they would have to wear a mask for an extended period of time. Of course, during the mask switching, many soldiers inhaled toxic chemicals and became casualties. From then On the Military Issued its own masks. Later Innovations Followed
        </Notes>
        </type>

<type> American Small Box Respirator (A.S.B.R.)
    <name>American Small Box Respirator (A.S.B.R.)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   The Training Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1917 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-001</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-001</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-001.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $325</price>
    <Notes>  The American Small Box Respirator (A.S.B.R.) was a hastily developed mask loosely based on the British Small Box Respirator. It used a similar carrier, filter and head harness. The mask's face piece was also designed so the wearer could wipe the eye pieces clean with a finger from the outside of the mask, again copying the British mask. But, soon after the A.S.B.R. went into production, it was found to have many shortcomings, particularly within the filter unit. So, the A.S.B.R. was quickly replaced by the Corrected English Model (see below). Remaining A.S.B.R.s had the top of the filter canister painted red, and the mask was then only used for drills and training exercises. Thus, it became known as the Training Mask. The A.S.B.R. is easily identified by the presence of the tall black and red filter canister and the lack of any type of exhale valve guard. While over 25,000 A.S.B.R.s were produced, the mask remains to be one of the more difficult US W.W.I masks to find today.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Corrected English Model (C.E.M.)
    <name>Corrected English Model (C.E.M.)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   C.E. Mask (Corrected English Mask)</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1917/1918 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-002</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-002</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-002.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $190</price>
    <Notes>  Perhaps the most commonly found of the US W.W.I masks is the Corrected English Model (C.E.M.). After the failure of the American Small Box Respirator, the C.E.M. was developed in an attempt to fix many of the problems with earlier box respirator designs. Several different developments were made over the years while the C.E.M. was in production, and before the end of W.W.I, nearly 2 million C.E.M. masks were produced. Because of the rapid pace of research at the time, several different variants of the C.E.M. were manufactured. The most common versions came with a yellow 'H' filter canister and a thin metal exhale valve guard. However, later versions of the mask used the improved 'J' type filter which was painted green. In addition, some later variants used a wider metal exhale valve guard to better protect the fragile, 'flapper' type exhale valve.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Corrected English Model (C.E.M.)
    <name>Corrected English Model (C.E.M.)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   C.E. Mask (Corrected English Mask)</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1917/1918 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-177</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-177</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-177.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $125</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the C.E.M. used celluloid eye pieces and had no exhale valve guard. This version clearly illustrates how many different modifications were made to this early design. It is also possible that this is an early version, made before any versions with exhale valve guards were introduced.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Corrected English Model (C.E.M.)
    <name>Corrected English Model (C.E.M.)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   C.E. Mask (Corrected English Mask)</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1917/1918 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare (size 5)</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-003</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-003</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-003.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $285</price>
    <Notes>  The C.E.M. mask was manufactured in five different sizes to accommodate different head and face shapes. Most C.E.M. masks have the size number stamped on the front of the mask and on the outside of the mask's carrier. Some masks were made in an extra wide size, and are typically marked as such (i.e. 4 WIDE) At right, a size 5 (the largest size) is pictured. The size 5 seems to be quite uncommon, while size 3 masks seem to be the most significantly produced.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Corrected English Model (C.E.M.)
    <name>Corrected English Model (C.E.M.)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   C.E. Mask (Corrected English Mask)</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1917/1918 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare (with black and yellow filter)</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-004</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-004</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-004.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $190</price>
    <Notes>  A rare variant of the C.E.M. was also assembled with a black and yellow painted filter canister. This is perhaps a specialized filter for certain hazards (like ammonia or carbon monoxide) or also maybe a faulty 'H' filter that was only used for training.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Corrected English Model (C.E.M.)
    <name>Corrected English Model (C.E.M.)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1917/1918 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-005</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-005</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-005.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $105</price>
    <Notes>  A later version of the C.E.M. Featured a green type 'J' filter canister and a different exhale valve guard made from wider pieces of metal. This most likely helped protect the rubber 'flapper type' exhale valve from getting torn off in the field. It might also be noted that the C.E.M. was manufactured with both glass eye pieces and celluloid eye pieces (glass however, seems to be more common). Also, most C.E.M. masks are usually stamped 'C.E.' on the chin just behind the exhale valve, making them easily identifiable. The C.E.M. can still be found in excellent condition with the flutter valve intact, but masks in this shape usually bring high prices on the collectors market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Corrected English Model (C.E.M.)
    <name>Corrected English Model (C.E.M.)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1917/1918 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-175</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-175</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-175.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $145</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the C.E.M. had a red painted filter. It is unknown if this is a post war modification or if the filter was painted red for some other reason (training, faulty, etc.). Either way, yet another interesting variant of the C.E.M. design.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Richardson, Flory &amp; Kops (R.F.K.) Gas Mask
    <name>Richardson, Flory &amp; Kops (R.F.K.) Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1918 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-006</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-006</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-006.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $145</price>
    <Notes>  The R.F.K. mask, named after three members of the Chemical Warfare Service (Ralph Richardson, E.L. Flory and Waldemar Kops), looks identical to the C.E.M. at a glance. However, there are quite a few differences. Mainly, the mask used a different head harness, consisting of two straps on either side of the forehead, as opposed to just one in the center as with the Corrected English Model. The R.F.K.'s face piece was also shaped a little differently than the C.E.M., giving it a wider appearance when worn. While more R.F.K. masks were produced during the war period, they seem to be somewhat more difficult to find, especially in good condition. The mask pictured at right still has the flapper type exhale valve intact, although completely hardened.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Connel Gas Mask
    <name>Connel Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Connell Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1919 </Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  USA</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-007</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-007</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-007.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $100+</price>
    <Notes>  The US Connel Gas Mask is an experimental gas mask made by the British for use by the US Chemical Warfare Service. The face piece was made of a combination of metal and canvas with an early foam rubber material used to create a face seal. The filter canister was suspended behind the wearers head and was connected to a single corrugated rubber tube that attached to an inlet on the left side of the face piece. Inside the mask, air was directed over the circular glass eye pieces to aid demisting. Exhaled air was pushed out through a rubber exhale valve (missing in photo) fitted to an opening on the front of the mask. It is unknown how many Connel masks were procured by the US, but it is unquestionably an extremely rare gas mask to find today.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Akron-Tissot (A.T.) Gas Mask
    <name>Akron-Tissot (A.T.) Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1918 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-008</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-008</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-008.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $75+</price>
    <Notes>  The A.T. Mask was made by the Akron Rubber Company (Akron, Ohio), and used the French Tissot principle. This being the idea of directing inhaled air over the eye pieces to keep them from fogging, a common problem with most early gas masks. There were at least two different variants of the A.T. Mask produced. One had olive painted eye piece frames (pictured at right) while another version had crimped black metal frames. The A.T. mask usually bears a red stamp on the side of the face piece indicating 'AT'. Due to the nature of the materials used to manufacture this mask, few remain today. When found, the A.T. Mask is usually in completely hardened condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Kops-Tissot (K.T.) Gas Mask
    <name>Kops-Tissot (K.T.) Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1918 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-009</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-009</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-009.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $100+</price>
    <Notes>  The K.T. Mask was another WWI mask that used the Tissot principle, and was developed by Waldemar Kops, a regular name in early respirator design. The K.T. was produced in at least two versions. The early version featured threaded eye piece frames and a yellow 'H' type filter canister. The later version (at right) featured pressed eye piece frames and a green 'J' type filter canister. Like the A.T. Mask, the K.T. Mask is also very scarce today, and when found is typically in poor condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Gas Mask, Mark I (Mouth Canister Type)
    <name>US Navy Gas Mask, Mark I (Mouth Canister Type)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1917 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-135</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-135</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-135.jpg</pic>
    <price> $325</price>
    <Notes>  This early Navy development was designed to combine the best elements of the German Gummischutzmaske and the British Small Box Respirator. This allowed for a high level of protection and comfort while allowing for a greater level of mobility (compared to other US gas masks in use at the time). Like the German Gummischutzmaske, the Navy Mark I was also issued in a similar metal carrying canister. However unlike the German Gummischutzmaske, the MK. I used a wide rubber flapper type exhale valve that protruded from the filter inlet stem. Like the C.E.M., The Navy Mouth Canister mask used nose clips and a snorkel like mouth piece on the inside. There were two versions of the Mouth Canister mask developed, one with filter support straps on the outside (at right) and one with the support straps on the inside (below). The Navy MK. I can still be found today on the collector's market in fair to good condition, but it is quite rare and usually expensive to obtain.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Gas Mask, Mark I (Mouth Canister Type)
    <name>US Navy Gas Mask, Mark I (Mouth Canister Type)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1917 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-010</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-010</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-010.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $325</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the Navy Mark I was most likely designed after the above version. While both versions are very similar, this example was manufactured with the filter support straps on the inside of the mask. In addition, wider head harness straps were also used, probably making the mask more durable overall. This version of the Mouth Canister Gas Mask seems to be more common than the above version.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Gas Mask, Mark II (Head Canister Type)
    <name>US Navy Gas Mask, Mark II (Head Canister Type)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1919 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Navy</Function>
    <Refrence> US-011</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-011</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-011.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $150</price>
    <Notes>  Of all the US developments during these early years, the Navy MK. II Head Canister Gas Mask is certainly the most peculiar. The filter canister was worn on top of the head as part of an integrated helmet-like, metal support system. Air was inhaled through an opening in the back of the filter canister and drawn through to the front of the canister and down into the mask via two short rubber hoses that connected just above the eye pieces. Exhaled air was directed up and out through a flapper type exhale valve located on the forehead of the mask. The mask was also issued with two rectangular 'filter pads' that were connected to a metal assembly that could be attached to the filter canister in the rear. These pads were used to capture smoke and other particles. The WWI US Navy Mark II is quite rare, and when found, is usually in very poor condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Kops, Tissot, Monro (K.T.M.) Gas Mask
    <name>Kops, Tissot, Monro (K.T.M.) Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Model 1919 Gas Mask, MI Service Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1919 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-012</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-012</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-012.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $325</price>
    <Notes>  After much trial and error during W.W.I, Waldemar Kops and Randolph Monro developed a new mask that once again used the Tissot principle for demisting. It was initially called the K.T.M. mask, but soon came to be known as the Model 1919. The mask's face piece was made from a special sheet of stockinet covered rubber, which was sewn together at the chin to create a proper face form. This gave the mask a higher level of protection and a better fit than any previous designs. In the years to follow leading up to the start of W.W.II, the K.T.M. went through many significant changes, particularly with the filter. Early versions of the mask used a blue painted box type filter canister that was continually modified until the standardization of the MIXA1 heavy- weight canister. The K.T.M. was finally standardized as the Army MI Service Gas Mask in 1921 after several changes to the filter, hose tube and carrier.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Kops, Tissot, Monro (K.T.M.) Gas Mask
    <name>Kops, Tissot, Monro (K.T.M.) Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Model 1919 Gas Mask, MI Service Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1919 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-013</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-013</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-013.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $325</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the K.T.M. is more or less identical to the above, original version. However, this version is fitted with a Type G Training Filter. Both versions of this mask are quite difficult to find today, particularly with an intact flapper type exhale valve, which is missing entirely from the specimen pictured to the right.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army MI Service Gas Mask
    <name>US Army MI Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Model 1919</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-127</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-127</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-127.jpg</pic>
    <price> $200</price>
    <Notes>  The MI Service gas mask was basically an upgraded version of the early K.T.M. Gas Mask (see above). It was what would eventually become the MIA1 Service Gas Mask and subsequently the widely produced MIA2 Service Gas Mask. At a glance, the MI appears to be identical to the MIA1 or MIA2, however this earlier version had several different features. Most notably, the eye piece frames were crimped instead of threaded. Also the filter canister used was of the early MV III type. The mask pictured to the right is very early, and used an older spring type head harness. The outside of face piece bears no size stamps or any other markings of any kind. Intact MI Service Masks are very difficult to find today, and when located are typically in deteriorated condition with hardened or missing 'flapper type' exhale valves.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army MIA1 Service Gas Mask
    <name>US Army MIA1 Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1920s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Navy</Function>
    <Refrence> US-014</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-014</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-014.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $200</price>
    <Notes>  The Army MIA1 Service Gas Mask served as an upgrade to the US MI Service Gas Mask. It used threaded eye piece frames, a slightly different face blank and a new MII head harness. The MIA1 also introduced a new filter canister that offered less breathing resistance and better filtering properties. The MIA1 was manufactured in 4 sizes, but was later replaced by the MIA2 which was made in one universal size (see below). The MIA1 is somewhat scarce today, but can still be found in mint, un-issued co nditio n.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army MIA2 Service Gas Mask
    <name>US Army MIA2 Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-015</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-015</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-015.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $130</price>
    <Notes>  The Army MIA2 Service Gas Mask is more or less identical to the MIA1 (above). However, the MIA2 was manufactured in one universal size, as opposed to 4 different sizes like the MIA1. The head harness was also sewn onto the face piece in a slightly different arrangement, probably to enhance comfort and fit. The face piece of the MIA2 is generally bigger and has a longer forehead; this again is most likely to accommodate the most common head sizes. The MIA2 was originally manufactured with a khaki stockinet face piece and was later issued with a gray stockinet face piece and a greenish-gray rubber hose (below). Both versions are becoming more and more difficult to locate on the collector's market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army MIA2 Service Gas Mask
    <name>US Army MIA2 Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-016</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-016</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-016.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $170</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the Army MIA2 Service Gas Mask is basically identical to the above version, but was manufactured with a gray colored stockinet face piece, a gray rubber exhale valve and a gray rubber hose tube. Both versions seem to be about equally as difficult to find today.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army/Navy MI Diaphragm Gas Mask
    <name>US Army/Navy MI Diaphragm Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1920s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-139</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-139</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-139.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $450</price>
    <Notes>  A modification of the MI face piece to fit a speech diaphragm resulted in the Mark I Diaphragm Gas Mask. This mask, designed by Randolph Monro, was used by both the Army and the Navy, and came in four different sizes. A large speech diaphragm was located on the front of the mask with a flutter type exhale valve and breathing tube connector just below. On the inside, dual metal pipes directed inhaled air over the eye pieces, applying the Tissot principle. The mask was slung in a standard 'kidney' shaped, khaki carrier. Future modifications to the Mark I resulted in the MIA1 Diaphragm Gas Mask and later the MII Diaphragm Gas Mask (see below). Also, a civilian version of this mask was made for use by miners and fireman (see US-107).</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army/Navy MIA1 Diaphragm Gas Mask
    <name>US Army/Navy MIA1 Diaphragm Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1920s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-017</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-017</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-017.jpg</pic>
    <price>  SOLD</price>
    <Notes>  The MIA1 Diaphragm Gas Mask is simply an updated version of the MI Diaphragm Gas Mask (see above). When the Army introduced the MIA1 Service Gas Mask (US-014), the Diaphragm gas mask was also updated. The crimped eye piece frames were replaced with threaded frames and the head harness was also updated. A few other slight changes were also incorporated, but the overall appearance of the Diaphragm gas mask stayed the same.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army/Navy MII Diaphragm Gas Mask
    <name>US Army/Navy MII Diaphragm Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-018</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-018</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-018.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $450</price>
    <Notes>  Further modifications to the diaphragm mask resulted in the MII Diaphragm Gas Mask. The MII used a peculiar setup with the speech diaphragm located on the front behind the flutter type exhale valve, which was pointed upward. Inhaled air was separated into two metal tubes that directed air flow over the eye pieces to help reduce fogging. These Tissot tubes are clearly visible through the glass eye pieces. The mask's face piece was manufactured in one universal size, making production faster and more cost effective. Today, both Mark I and Mark II Diaphragm Gas Masks are quite rare, making them highly collectable early US respirato rs.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army/Navy MII Diaphragm Gas Mask
    <name>US Army/Navy MII Diaphragm Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-019</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-019</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-019.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $200+</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the Mark II Diaphragm Gas Mask is basically identical to the above version, but varies slightly. Firstly, the mask pictured to the right used an old style, spring type head harness (see details). In addition, this mask was made with black rubber as opposed to tan rubber used with the above version. The angle tube used to connect the filter canister is also smaller and shorter than the above version. Both variants are quite rare, and when found are often in very poor condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M2 Training Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M2 Training Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   MI Training Mask (early nomenclature)</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1939 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-020</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-020</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-020.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $200+</price>
    <Notes>  The first US gas mask to use a fully molded rubber face piece was the MI Training Gas Mask. The face blank, later designated the M2 face piece, went on to be the basis for most WWII US gas masks to follow. The Training Mask was equipped with a long filter canister, also designated the MI, attached directly to the bottom of the mask. Pictured to the right is the first model of the Training mask which had the MIV "Acushnet" type exhale valve instead of the later more widely used MV "Connel" type exhale valve. The MI also did not have rifle skids, as did later versions. This early version is quite scarce, as it was not made in significant enough numbers before it was replaced by the MIA1.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M2A1 Training Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M2A1 Training Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   MIA1 Training Mask (early nomenclature)</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1939 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-021</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-021</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-021.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $360</price>
    <Notes>  Soon after the MI Training Gas Mask went into production, it was updated and renamed the MIA1 Training Gas Mask. This version of the Training mask used a new face piece mold which included "rifle skids", a feature designed to prevent the wearer's rifle from getting caught on the lower head harness rivets when aiming from the shoulder position. The MIA1 also did away with the early MIV "Acushnet" type exhale valve, replacing it with an updated MV "Connel" style valve. Early MIA1s were made of all black rubber, like the MI, but were later made from the more common greenish-gray rubber.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M2A1 Training Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M2A1 Training Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   MIA1 Training Mask (early nomenclature)</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1939 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-022</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-022</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-022.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $340</price>
    <Notes>  The MIA1 mask pictured to the right is more or less the same as the version above, however this one was manufactured by Firestone, giving it a slightly different appearance from the Acushnet versions pictured above. There were several different companies making gas masks for the US Army at the time, and early on there were slightly different molds being used at varying factories. In some cases, this posed a problem for manufactures constructing standard hardware, head harnesses and filter units for the early masks. Many issues such as this came about during the early years of gas mask experimentation, thus keeping gas mask evolution on the move.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M2A1 Training Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M2A1 Training Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   MIA1 Training Mask (early nomenclature)</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1939 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-023</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-023</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-023.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $105</price>
    <Notes>  This example of the MIA1 was also made by Firestone, but it was molded from greenish-gray colored rubber. The filter unit was also painted gray instead of olive green. This version of the Training Mask was manufactured in large quantities, and was used extensively by military personnel and civilians alike stationed on islands in the Pacific. Around this time, the US Chemical Warfare Service also redesigned their nomenclature system, getting away entirely from using Roman numerals. The designation for the Training Mask was changed to M2 (and M2A1 respectively).</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M2A1 Training Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M2A1 Training Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   US Army M2A2 Training Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-024</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-024</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-024.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $290</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the Training Mask, also designated the M2A1, used a M8 type exhale valve. It is possible that this version was made from M2A2 Service Gas Masks. However it is possible that these were manufactured from the start as Training Gas Masks, but with updated M8 exhale valves. These later versions do not seem to be as common as the previous version with the MV exhale valve.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M2A1 Service Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M2A1 Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1939/1940 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-025</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-025</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-025.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $175</price>
    <Notes>  The M2A1 Service Gas Mask used the same face piece and exhale valve setup as the M2A1 Training Gas Mask (above). However, a long rubber breathing tube with a MIXA1 filter canister attached was used instead of the MI training filter. The M2A1 Service Gas Mask is not quite as common as the later service masks making it somewhat difficult to find on the collector's market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M2A2 Service Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M2A2 Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1939/1940 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-026</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-026</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-026.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $165</price>
    <Notes>  A modification of the the exhale valve of the M2A1 Service Gas Mask resulted in the M2A2 Service Gas Mask. The masks are identical otherwise. This mask is what would ultimately be the basis for the later M3 and M4 series service masks. The main problem with the M2 series service was the lack of in internal nose cup to reduce fogging and the heavyweight filter canister. Both of these issues were addressed with the introduction of the M3 and M4 series Lightweight Service Gas Masks. The M2A2 was manufactured in large numbers and can still be frequently found today in very good condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M2A2 Service Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M2A2 Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1941 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-205</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-205</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-205.jpg</pic>
    <price> $250</price>
    <Notes>  This variant of the M2A2 was manufactured by Goodyear and is basically the same as the above mask. This one however used a gray MIVA1 filter canister, which may be experimental. The mask's face piece appears to be an early type of black rubber, but not neoprene. This rare mask is most likely an experimental or prototype design made during the early years of WWII.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M2A2 Special Oil Vapor Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M2A2 Special Oil Vapor Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-027</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-027</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-027.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $250</price>
    <Notes>  Sometime during the 1940s, the US Army manufactured several "Standardized Special Gas Masks". Among these special gas masks were the M2A2 Acid Vapor Gas Mask, the M2A2 Ammonia Gas Mask, the M2A2 HCN Gas Mask and the M2A2 Oil Vapor Gas Mask (at right). Each came equipped with a specially labeled filter canister designed to protect against a specific gas. For all practical purposes the mask was identical to the M2A2 Service Gas Mask, but had no rifle skids and a slightly different head harness assembly (identical to the M3 series). This is certainly one of the best examples of how confusing early US nomenclature can be. These special gas masks are quite scarce today as few were manufactured, obviously due to a small demand.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M3-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M3-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-028</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-028</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-028.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $140</price>
    <Notes>  The Army M3-10A1-6 was a modification of the earlier M2A2 Service Gas Mask. The mask was designed to be lighter, so a shorter breathing tube was used with a lightweight M10A1 filter canister fixed to the end. An inner oronasal cup was also incorporated to reduce fogging of the eye pieces. The head harness was also riveted onto the face piece differently, so as to not require rifle skids. This factor makes the M3-10A1-6 easy to distinguish from the other lightweight service gas masks. The M3-10A1-6 was made in fairly significant numbers but it is still somewhat difficult to find today.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M3-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M3-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-029</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-029</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-029.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $145</price>
    <Notes>  More commonly found is the black neoprene rubber M3-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask. Because of natural rubber shortages, an alternative synthetic rubber was in need, and thus Neoprene was used. While Neoprene met most of the demands required to construct a protective mask, the synthetic rubber was found to have a problem when exposed to colder weather. The face piece would get stiff and difficult to don, a condition known as "cold-set". This problem led to the eventual elimination of Neoprene rubber gas masks. However, it is the M3-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask which was converted post production into the the well known M5-11-7 Assault Gas Mask.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M3-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask  (L - Large Sized Version)
    <name>US Army M3-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask  (L - Large Sized Version)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-030</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-030</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-030.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $220</price>
    <Notes>  The version of the M3-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask pictured to the right is a rare size large mask. The standard was to produce service masks in one universal size (marked with a large letter 'U' on the forehead). There was however a need to accommodate a smaller number of otherwise abnormally large or small head sizes, thus small numbers of these large sized masks were produced with a large letter 'L' on the forehead. It should also be noted that a 'SS' or 'Super Small' version of some service masks were produced during the late war years as well (see below).</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M3A1-10A1-6 Lightweight Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M3A1-10A1-6 Lightweight Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-031</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-031</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-031.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $110</price>
    <Notes>  The Army M3A1-10A1-6 is identical to the M3-10A1-6 but used a C15 exhale valve as opposed to the more common M8 exhale valve. The same carrier, filter, inner oronasal cup and face blank was used. For some reason the M3A1 seems to be slightly more common than the earlier M3, but for the most part these masks are becoming harder to find.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M4-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M4-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-032</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-032</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-032.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $125</price>
    <Notes>  Another modification to the M2A2 Service Gas Mask yielded the M4-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask. These masks were typically made with an olive drab rubber face piece and breathing tube, but occasionally Neoprene breathing tubes were fitted. It must also be noted that these masks are commonly found with different colors of paint, elastic and plastic dye, as several different manufacturers were constructing the masks towards the end of the war. Notice the rifle skid moldings and the same head harness rivet placement as the M2A2. The only difference between the M4 and the later M4A1 was that the M4 used a M8 exhale valve and the M4A1 used a C15 exhale valve. Both the M4 and M4A1 seem to be much more common than the M3 series lightweight service gas masks.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M4-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M4-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-033</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-033</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-033.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $100</price>
    <Notes>  This M4-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask is pictured to demonstrate the variation in colors commonly found with these masks. The example pictured to the right was made by Firestone Tire &amp; Rubber Company, whereas the above example is was made by General Tire &amp; Rubber Company. It must also be noted that some M4s lack an inner nose cup, possibly due to rubber shortages.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M4-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask (SS - Super Small Version)
    <name>US Army M4-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask (SS - Super Small Version)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c . 1944</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-034</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-034</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-034.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $85 </price>
    <Notes>  Another interesting variation of the M4-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask is the 'SS' version (super small version). Typically, the M4 was issued in one universal face piece size (marked with a large letter 'U' on the forehead) making the super small version (marked with the letters 'SS' on the forehead) somewhat rare. There are several other notable differences as well. Because of the smaller size, the mask was not manufactured with an inner oronasal nose cup, and the head harness pad was also left out. These differences, could only be due to the smaller face piece assembly.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M4A1-10A1-6 Lightweight Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M4A1-10A1-6 Lightweight Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-035</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-035</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-035.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $110</price>
    <Notes>  A few slight modifications to the M4-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask yielded the M4A1-10A1-6 Lightweight Service Gas Mask. These masks were typically made with an olive drab rubber face piece and breathing tube, but occasionally Neoprene breathing tubes were fitted. Notice the rifle skid moldings and the same head harness rivet placement as the M4. The main difference between the M4 and the M4A1 was the exhale valve.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M5-11-7 Assault Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M5-11-7 Assault Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Combat Service Gas Mask, Invasion Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-036</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-036</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-036.jpg</pic>
    <price> $175</price>
    <Notes>  The US Army Assault Gas Mask is quite possibly the most sought after WWII US gas mask due to the fact that it is this mask that was carried during the D-day Invasion of Normandy. The M5-11-7 was originally inspired by the British MK. I Light Anti-Gas Respirator and was intended to be a light weight mask that soldiers could carry during amphibious assaults. Thus, the mask was issued with a carrier made of a waterproof rubberized duck material which doubled as a floatation device when in use. The M5-11-7 was quickly phased out when it was discovered that the neoprene face piece was subject to a hardening known as "cold-set". While the M5-11-7 always brings a high price on the surplus/collector's market, it is still quite common and can be found in mint, un-issued condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M8 Snout-Type Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M8 Snout-Type Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-037</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-037</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-037.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $185</price>
    <Notes>  The Army M8 Snout Type gas mask is quite interesting in that is was constructed from un-issued M4A1 Lightweight Service Gas Masks as a quick replacement for the M5 Assault Gas Mask after it was found to have problems with "cold-set". A 60mm filter inlet was mounted to the chin of the face piece to allow the use of the standard M11 drum type canister. Because this mask was needed toward the end of WWII, few were manufactured Thus, it is somewhat difficult to find today.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M3 Diaphragm Gas Mask (1941 Mfg.)
    <name>US Army M3 Diaphragm Gas Mask (1941 Mfg.)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-038</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-038</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-038.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $115</price>
    <Notes>  In order to accommodate the necessity for a gas mask with an able speech diaphragm, the M3 Diaphragm Gas Mask was introduced. The front of the face piece was fitted with a metal speech diaphragm assembly which was situated just above a flutter type exhale valve. This configuration meant that the breathing tube could not be connected directly to the face piece. Instead, a hard plastic tube was fitted into two holes on either side of the face piece with the breathing tube connected to the center of the tube (angled slightly forward). The M3 Diaphragm mask was manufactured in significant numbers, and is thus not difficult to locate on the collector's market, however this early version with black metal parts and black head harness seems to be more scarce.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M3 Diaphragm Gas Mask (1943 Mfg.)
    <name>US Army M3 Diaphragm Gas Mask (1943 Mfg.)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-039</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-039</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-039.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $115</price>
    <Notes>  This M3 Diaphragm Gas Mask is identical to the above mask in design, but has olive-drab painted metal parts and a matching head harness. This variation in color may simply be a result of different manufacturers, although there may be a functional purpose to color changes. The all green version pictured to the right seems to be the most commonly found on the collector's market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M3A1 Diaphragm Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M3A1 Diaphragm Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1942 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common/Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States
</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-040</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-040</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-040.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $95 </price>
    <Notes>  A modification to the speech diaphragm and exhale valve assembly of the M3 Diaphragm Gas Mask lead to the M3A1 Diaphragm Gas Mask. The M3A1 was essentially identical to the M3, but a new plastic voice-mitter/exhale valve assembly was used in place of the earlier metal type. The new parts were most likely functionally superior to the previous types as well as lighter. The M3A1 Diaphragm Gas Mask was manufactured in large numbers, thus is quite common on the collector's market today.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army Gas Mask (Reconditioned For Training)
    <name>US Army Gas Mask (Reconditioned For Training)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-192</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-192</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-192.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $75</price>
    <Notes>  After WWII, several left-over gas masks were "reconditioned" and used for training purposes. This particular mask, was made from M3A1 Diaphragm parts and equipped with a M10A1 filter canister. The mask's carrier was also altered to reflect that the mask was only to be used for training purposes.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army MI-I-5 Optical Gas Mask
    <name>US Army MI-I-5 Optical Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Army Artillery Gas Mask, Army Tank Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1941 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-041</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-041</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-041.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $300</price>
    <Notes>  During the early stages of gas mask development in 1920s, it was apparent that a gas mask for use with optical sighting devices (like scopes and binoculars) was needed. In 1941, the Army designed and standardized the Army MI-I-5 Optical Gas Mask. It was more or less identical to the Navy version (below) but the two do have some significant differences. The distance between the small round eye pieces could be adjusted via a threaded rod, accommodating a wide range of head sizes. The mask's filter canister was suspended behind the wearer's neck by means of a metal clip on the filter that was attached to a canvas sleeve sewn onto the head harness. Inhaled air was drawn through a horizontal slit in the filter. Today, the Army MI Optical Gas Mask is among the rarest of the WWII US gas masks. While the Army version was not made in significant numbers, the Navy Diaphragm Optical Gas Mask was manufactured and issued in quantity to soldiers aboard ships.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army MI-I-5 Optical Gas Mask
    <name>US Army MI-I-5 Optical Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   US NDO Mark I Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1941 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-042</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-042</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-042.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $300</price>
    <Notes>  This US optical gas mask is most likely an updated Army version of the above green type. This mask is what would later be molded with the USN face piece and designated the Navy Diaphragm Optical (NDO) Mark I Gas Mask (see below). These early Army version are much more rare than the US Navy versions which were made in more significant numbers.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Diaphragm Optical (NDO) Mark I Gas Mask
    <name>US Navy Diaphragm Optical (NDO) Mark I Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1941 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Navy</Function>
    <Refrence> US-043</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-043</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-043.jpg</pic>
    <price> $140</price>
    <Notes>  For the Navy, a gas masks that could be used with optical sighting devices was in demand during WWII. As a result, a modified version of the Army MI Optical Gas Mask was made for use aboard ships. It was designated the Navy Diaphragm Optical Gas Mask, Mark I. Like the Army version, the distance between the small round eye pieces could be adjusted via a threaded rod, accommodating a wide range of head sizes. The mask's filter canister was suspended behind the wearer's neck with a metal clip, which was attached to the back of the head harness. From a series of small holes along the back of the filter, inhaled air was drawn through two corrugated rubber tubes and forced over the eye pieces to help keep them from fogging. While the N.D.O. Mark I is not as common as the later Navy Diaphragm masks, it is still fairly easy to find on the collector's market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army/Navy Diaphragm Gas Mask
    <name>US Army/Navy Diaphragm Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1938 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army/Navy</Function>
    <Refrence> US-206</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-206</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-206.jpg</pic>
    <price> $140</price>
    <Notes>  This early diaphragm mask was manufactured in 1938, and used the old style filter suspension method (see DETAILS below). This design, is what would eventually become standardized by the Navy, as the ND Mark III (see below). Both this version and the regular Navy version are quite similar, however this version does not bear a USN mold marking on the forehead, and has the older type filter clip on the back. This particular mask may have been used by the Army, or it may simply be an early production ND Mark III.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Diaphragm (ND) Mark III Gas Mask
    <name>US Navy Diaphragm (ND) Mark III Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1942 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Navy</Function>
    <Refrence> US-044</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-044</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-044.jpg</pic>
    <price> $125</price>
    <Notes>  Following the same design as the earlier N.D.O. Mark I, the ND Mark III was manufactured. This mask was not an optical mask, but did have special elliptically shaped eye pieces designed to enhance peripheral vision. This is the only difference between the Mark I and the Mark III. The filter canister was suspended behind the neck in the same manner as well. This configuration was used to give the soldier's head more freedom while maneuvering in the confines of a ship. The Mark III was manufactured in significant enough numbers to make it somewhat common today, but it was replaced by the Mark IV, which was manufactured towards the end of the war, and in much greater numbers.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Diaphragm (ND) Mark IV Gas Mask
    <name>US Navy Diaphragm (ND) Mark IV Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Navy</Function>
    <Refrence> US-045</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-045</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-045.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $80 </price>
    <Notes>  The Navy Diaphragm Mark IV was nothing more than an improved Mark III. It was found that the elliptical eye pieces used on the Mark III where not as efficient as the larger triangular eye pieces used with the Mark IV. This is the only difference between the two masks. The Mark IV is perhaps one of the most commonly found W.W.II Navy masks today. It can still be found in un-issued condition packed inside it's original cardboard box.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Diaphragm (ND) Mark IV Gas Mask (Modified for shallow water diving)
    <name>US Navy Diaphragm (ND) Mark IV Gas Mask (Modified for shallow water diving)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Damage-Control Hose Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944/1945</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Navy</Function>
    <Refrence> US-131</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-131</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-131.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $300+</price>
    <Notes>  In 1944 the Navy published several documents outlining the use of existing ND Mark III and IV gas masks for shallow water diving purposes. These masks were altered aboard ships and stowed in "damage-control" repair lockers. If needed, a diver could don the mask, which was connected to a air supply line, and dive up to depths of 36 feet. The peculiar example pictured to the right appears to fit the description of such modified gas masks almost perfectly. However, the example pictured to the right features an early Western Electric microphone in place of the diaphragm. The microphone connection cord has been cut, which means it could have been quite long (long enough for a 36 foot dive), and would also suggest that the microphone is water-proof as well as air-tight. The filter canister was removed and in place a "T" shaped brass connector was inserted and sealed with cement. These "on-the-fly" modified gas masks are quite scarce today in any condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1939 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-046</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-046</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-046.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $100+</price>
    <Notes>  The modified Mark III Diaphragm mask pictured to the right was manufactured by Acushnet and is dated 1939. The face piece used the US Army mold, which would make this mask an Army used mask and not a Navy mask, as with the below example. These modified Mark III Diaphragm masks may have been used as special purpose masks connected to a supplied air system, but their true function is not known.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1942 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-132</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-132</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-132.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $275</price>
    <Notes>  The modified Mark III Diaphragm mask pictured to the right was manufactured by MSA and is dated 1942. The face piece used the US Navy mold, which would make this mask an Navy used mask and not an Army mask, as with the above example. These modified Mark III Diaphragm masks may have been used as special purpose masks connected to a supplied air system, but their true function is not known.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Oxygen Rescue Breathing Apparatus
    <name>US Navy Oxygen Rescue Breathing Apparatus</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Type A-I (NORBA Type A-1)</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1941</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Navy)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-047</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-047</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-047.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $300</price>
    <Notes>  The Navy Oxygen Rescue Breathing Apparatus was made from modified ND Mark III and Mark IV gas mask molds and was housed in a large gray trunk (see DETAILS). The mask was used as a short term oxygen generating rescue apparatus for emergency situations where the oxygen level in the air was too low to sustain life, or other harmful gases were present. When the canister seal was broken, a chemical reaction forced oxygen into a large bladder that was worn around the front of the body. Expired air was breathed back into the canister and recycled back into oxygen for re-breathing. Each canister could be used for 30 to 45 minutes before a fresh canister had to be installed. A starter valve on the front of the mask allowed the wearer to breath outside air while the chemical reaction inflated the breathing bag with oxygen. Once this process was complete, the starter valve could be closed and re-breathing could begin. The N.O.R.B.A. is somewhat rare today, and when found most are in poor and/or incomplete condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Smoke Mask, Model NM
    <name>US Navy Smoke Mask, Model NM</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1941 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Navy)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-130</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-130</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-130.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $290</price>
    <Notes>  The Navy Smoke Mask Model NM is very similar to the NORBA Type A-1 (above). The face piece assembly is virtually identical, but the rebreathing unit was quite different (see details). The Navy Smoke Mask was most likely employed for rescue work where high levels of smoke filled confined spaces and oxygen levels were too low to sustain life. The Model NM seems to be more commonly found today on the surplus market when compared with the other Navy rebreathers, but it is nonetheless rare.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Oxygen Rescue Breathing Apparatus
    <name>US Navy Oxygen Rescue Breathing Apparatus</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Type A-3 (NORBA Type A-3)</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1980s</Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Navy)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-186</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-186</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-186.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $60 </price>
    <Notes>  The NORBA Type A-3 was an updated version of the Navy's earlier rebreathers. The Type A-3 used a face piece based on the Navy Diaphragm Mark IV gas mask from WWII, and went on to be used well into the 1980s before it was replaced by a newer design. The Type A-3 is somewhat difficult to find today, as are most Navy rebreather units.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Oxygen Breathing Apparatus, Type B
    <name>US Navy Oxygen Breathing Apparatus, Type B</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Navy)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-193</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-193</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-193.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $225</price>
    <Notes>  The Navy Oxygen Breathing Apparatus Type B was a smaller rebreather unit that was most likely used for escape purposes. The unit came with a small half mask which was attached to the rebreather via a small corrugated hose. The mask also came equipped with a speech diaphragm identical to those used with all of the Navy masks from the WWII era. Also included was a pair of Willson safety goggles and several replacement canisters. The unit was stowed in a large wooden crate.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Oxygen Rebreathing Apparatus -
    <name>US Navy Oxygen Rebreathing Apparatus -</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Central Oxygen Supply Type</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1942 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Navy)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-199</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-199</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-199.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $375</price>
    <Notes>  The Central Supply Type Oxygen Rebreathing Apparatus was designed to be used by aviators at high altitudes, by supplying them with rebreathable air containing a high percentage of oxygen. The unit could be hooked up to a central oxygen reservoir for prolonged use. The unit could be either carried or stowed near the wearer during use. These bulky rebreathers are quite rare today, but when found are typically in un-issued co nditio n.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M2-10-6 Lightweight Optical Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M2-10-6 Lightweight Optical Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Army)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-191</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-191</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-191.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $675</price>
    <Notes>  The M2-10-6 was a new light-weight optical mask which took design elements from several earlier US Army masks. The optical eye pieces were identical to the Army MI-I-5 Optical Gas Mask, while the exhale valve/speech diaphragm assembly was identical to the M3A1 Diaphragm Gas Mask. Instead of carrying the filter canister behind the head (as with previous optical masks), the M2-10-6 used a M10 Filter canister attached to a long corrugated rubber hose, basically identical to the M3 and M4 series light-weight service masks. The M2-10-6 was most likely not manufactured in significant numbers, as this mask is quite scarce today. In the early 1950s, it was replaced by the more common M2-10A1-6 Lightweight Optical Gas Mask (see below).</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M2-10A1-6 Lightweight Optical Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M2-10A1-6 Lightweight Optical Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1952 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Army)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-048</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-048</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-048.jpg</pic>
    <price> $600</price>
    <Notes>  The M2-10A1-6 is perhaps one of the strangest looking US gas masks. The speech diaphragm was protected by a metal mesh-like material giving it a peculiar appearance. The M2-10A1-6 used the same adjustable eye pieces that were used on the earlier Army Optical Gas Masks and the N.D.O. Mark I. A lightweight M10A1 filter canister was attached to the mask via a corrugated rubber breathing tube. The mask's main purpose was to provide the Army with a gas mask that could be accurately used with optical sighting devices like scopes and binoculars. The M2-10A1-6 was manufactured in quantity, and it can be found fairly easily with a little searching, and often in mint un-issued condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Diaphragm (ND) Gas Mask, Mark V
    <name>US Navy Diaphragm (ND) Gas Mask, Mark V</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1957 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Navy)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-049</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-049</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-049.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $60 </price>
    <Notes>  The US Navy Mark V Gas Mask is interesting in that it is the only US gas mask to use this particular setup; the design is nothing like the earlier Navy diaphragm gas masks. The Mark V used a single plastic visor type eye piece, which offered an excellent field of view, but on the same token was prone to fogging as there was no inner mask installed. An adjustable five strap rubber head harness was used for suspension and two C1 filter discs were used for filtration. The speech diaphragm and exhale valve are clearly visible on the front of the mask. The Mark V came in a special gray fabric carrier that was reinforced with an angled piece of flat metal. The ND Mark V can be found readily on the surplus market in excellent condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US E15R3 Protective Mask Headpiece
    <name>US E15R3 Protective Mask Headpiece</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s/1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-204</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-204</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-204.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $300+</price>
    <Notes>  This experimental mask was most likely designed during the testing of various types of gas hoods for use during decontamination duty. The E15R3 consisted of a butyl hood which was incorporated with a half-mask and head harness on the inside. Two large circular eye pieces were also fitted directly to the hood. Unlike most protective mask hoods, this device was intended to be a standalone mask, rather than a hood that could be worn over a standard issue respirator. The E15R3 pictured here, is shown with a MSA Rocket Propellant filter canister.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army E48 Gas Mask
    <name>US Army E48 Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   E19R25 (original M.I.T. designation)</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. late 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Army)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-050</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-050</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-050.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $490</price>
    <Notes>  After the failure of the M5 Assault Gas Mask, a new lightweight combat gas mask was in demand. The E48, later standardized as the M9 Field Protective Mask, was the basis for one of the most successful gas mask designs ever. For the most part, the E48 is identical to the standardized M9, however both the E48 and several early M9 gas masks were made from black rubber instead of the more common gray rubber used for the bulk of all M9 and M9A1 gas masks manufactured. Because the E48 was technically a prototype mask, it is not commonly found on the collector's market and is quite rare today in any condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M9 Field Protective Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M9 Field Protective Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Army)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-051</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-051</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-051.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $385</price>
    <Notes>  The US Army M9 Field Protective Gas Mask is perhaps one of the most successful gas mask designs ever. It remained in use for approximately two decades and it has been copied by at least five countries. The M9 owes it's design to the earlier US E48 gas mask, which was an experimental upgrade based on the Army M5 Assault Gas Mask. The M9 pictured to the right is an early production example with a face piece made entirely from black rubber like the prototype E48 shown above. It is dated 1952. Aside from the use of black rubber, this M9 is identical to the standard gray rubber production model (see below).</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M9/M9A1 Field Protective Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M9/M9A1 Field Protective Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1951 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian (Army/Police)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-052</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-052</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-052.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $40</price>
    <Notes>  The US Army M9 Field Protective Gas Mask is perhaps one of the most successful gas mask designs ever. It remained in use for approximately two decades and it has been copied by at least five countries. The only difference between the M9 and M9A1 are the carriers, the masks themselves are identical. The M9 design, was basically an upgraded version of the US M5-11-7 Assault Service Gas Mask. It used the same 60mm M11 drum type filter canister that was attached to the side of the mask. The M9 was most commonly manufactured with the filter inlet on the left side, however, a right side filer inlet version was also made. This was to accommodate left handed personnel during weapon sighting. Because the M9 was in service for so many years, it is now one of the most commonly found US gas masks on the surplus market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M9/M9A1 Field Protective Gas Mask (Right sided filter inlet)
    <name>US Army M9/M9A1 Field Protective Gas Mask (Right sided filter inlet)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1951</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian (Army/Police)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-053</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-053</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-053.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $40 </price>
    <Notes>  This version of the US Army M9 Field Protective mask is basically identical to the above version, but was manufactured with the filter inlet on the right side. This was to accommodate left-handed soldiers when sighting their rifles. M9s with the filter on the right side are slightly more difficult to find today as fewer were manufactured.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M15 Compressed Air Breathing Apparatus
    <name>US Army M15 Compressed Air Breathing Apparatus</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c . 1950s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Army)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-054</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-054</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-054.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $245</price>
    <Notes>  The M15 Compressed Air Breathing Apparatus used the M9 face piece with a corrugated rubber hose attached to the side instead of the standard M11 filter. The hose was connected to two compressed air tanks that allowed closed circuit breathing. The M15 setup was most likely used for emergency situations where the oxygen levels were too low to sustain life. The heavy air canisters were strapped to a harness that allowed the wearer to sling the apparatus around the back. The M15 Compressed Air Breathing Apparatus is quite rare today as few were most likely manufactured.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army ABC-M21 Rocket Propellant Gas Mask
    <name>US Army ABC-M21 Rocket Propellant Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s </Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-055</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-055</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-055.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $150+</price>
    <Notes>  Like the M15 Compressed Air Breathing Apparatus, the ABC-M21 Rocket Propellant Gas Mask also used a standard M9 face piece. The corrugated rubber hose attached to the side of the mask was connected to a large filter manufactured to protect against rocket fuel fumes. The heavy filter canister was carried inside a leather sling and was worn around the wearer's neck. This setup is also very scarce today as few were likely manufactured.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US MI-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask
    <name>US MI-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1941 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-056</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-056</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-056.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $290</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the MI-I-I Noncombatant gas mask is certainly the most scarce, and it is most likely the earliest version manufactured. A tan fabric material was used for the face blank as opposed to the more common olive green rubberized fabric used with the later types. This early version used a MIV button type exhale valve instead of the M8 exhale valve (which was used on the later MIA2-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask).</Notes>
</type>

<type> US MI-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask
    <name>US MI-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1941 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-198</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-198</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-198.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $290</price>
    <Notes>  This MI-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask is very similar to the above version, and without a doubt, just as rare. It is for the most part identical, but varies in color. It is possible that these two masks were manufactured by different companies, attributing to these minor differences.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US MI-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask
    <name>US MI-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1941 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-057</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-057</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-057.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $190</price>
    <Notes>  Pictured to the right, is the more common of the two MI-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask versions. This one used a rubberized fabric face piece that was stitched together in the same manner as the previous version. While this version is more common that the above version, it is still quite scarce on the collector's market today. It also has a MIV button type exhale valve instead of the M8 exhale valve (a distinguishing characteristic between the MI and MIA2 Noncombatant Gas Masks).</Notes>
</type>

<type> US MIA2-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask
    <name>US MIA2-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1943 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-058</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-058</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-058.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $25</price>
    <Notes>  Perhaps the most commonly found US gas mask from the W.W.II era is the MIA2-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask. It is not difficult to find these masks still in the original cardboard box. The face piece was made of a thin piece of rubberized material that was more comfortable than the earlier MI-I-I. The chin area was shaped to accommodate the wearers chin and thus created a better fit. The MIV button type exhale valve was replaced with the widely used M8 exhale valve. The large fixed filter was secured in place with a metal band as opposed to a rubber band, making it more durable and less likely to leak.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US MIA2-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask (Child Size)
    <name>US MIA2-I-I Noncombatant Gas Mask (Child Size)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1943 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-059</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-059</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-059.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $35 </price>
    <Notes>  The only difference between this mask and the above mask is the size. This version was specially designed for young children, but all of the same components were used. Only the face piece itself was smaller. The MIA2-I-I (Child Size) is for the most part as easily found as the common adult size, but does require a bit more searching.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US M2-2-1 Noncombatant Gas Mask (Small Child)
    <name>US M2-2-1 Noncombatant Gas Mask (Small Child)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1943 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-060</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-060</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-060.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $80 </price>
    <Notes>  The M2-2-1 Small Child Noncombatant gas mask is certainly one of the tiniest gas masks ever made. It was considerably smaller than the MIA2-I-I Child Size Noncombatant Gas Mask and featured only a single plastic eye piece instead of two. Perhaps the most notable thing about the M2-2-1 is how similar it is to the US Mickey Mouse Gas Mask (not pictured) which used the same basic setup. The M2-2-1 can still be found today in excellent condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy Civilian-1 (NC-1) Gas Mask
    <name>US Navy Civilian-1 (NC-1) Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1941 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-061</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-061</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-061.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $50 </price>
    <Notes>  The NC-1 gas mask was designed to be used by civil defense teams operating in conjunction with the US Navy. The mask had a single eye piece made of flexible clear plastic. The NC-1 used two bilateral filter disks, identical to the ones used on the M6-12-8 Dog Gas Mask. A rubber flapper type exhale valve protruded downward from the front of the mask. An elastic head harness was used for suspension. The NC-1 is still somewhat common today, and it can be found in mint condition in the original cardboard box, however, the filters are somewhat more difficult to find on their own.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Prototype Child Protector
    <name>Prototype Child Protector</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-203</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-203</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-203.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $250</price>
    <Notes>  This early experimental child protector was basically a rubber suit that covered the child's entire upper body, arms and hands. A waist string could be tightened around the child's hips to create an airtight seal. Once properly adjusted, filtered air was pumped in via a hose and bellows attached to the left side of the suit. The bellows pumped air through a standard US M11 drum type filter canister which was held in place with a fabric strap. This experimental child protector is very similar to the German Gasjackchen, and was likely based on this design.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US M1 Infant Protector
    <name>US M1 Infant Protector</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-062</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-062</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-062.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $415</price>
    <Notes>  The M1 Infant Protector was introduced to fulfill the need for an adequate civilian device for protecting infants and very young children. Similar to the German infant protector of the same era, the M1 Infant Protector used a bellows system to pump in filtered air. Attached to the bellows was a standard M10A1 filter canister. A single piece of clear plastic was used for viewing the child while the device was in use. A draw-string was used to tighten and tie off the opening of the unit to create the gas proof seal. The whole unit was quite light and could be carried easily when folded up. The M1 infant protector is now quite scarce and difficult to locate on the collector's market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M4 Horse Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M4 Horse Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1942 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-194</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-194</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-194.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $135</price>
    <Notes>  The Army M4 Horse Gas Mask is one of two WWII issue respirators designed for horses. The M5 horse gas mask (see below) was nearly identical to the M4. The only difference between the two was found in the placement of the two large filter canisters. With the M4, one filter was carried on each shoulder of the horse, while with the M5, both filters were carried on the right shoulder of the horse leaving the left shoulder open for calvary soldiers to sling their rifles. The M4 Horse Gas Mask is a very large contraption, and because of this most horse masks were likely disposed of after the war. Surviving examples of either type are extremely rare, and often in incomplete or damaged condition. See the DETAILS page for an expanded view of the complete M4 Gas Mask assembly.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M5 Horse Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M5 Horse Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1942 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-197</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-197</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-197.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $150</price>
    <Notes>  The Army M5 Horse Gas Mask is one of two WWII issue respirators designed for horses. The M4 horse gas mask (see above) was nearly identical to the M5. The only difference between the two was found in the placement of the two large filter canisters. With the M4, one filter was carried on each shoulder of the horse, while with the M5, both filters were carried on the right shoulder of the horse leaving the left shoulder open for calvary soldiers to sling their rifles. The M5 Horse Gas Mask is a very large contraption, and because of this most horse masks were likely disposed of after the war. Surviving examples of either type are extremely rare, and often in incomplete or damaged condition. See the DETAILS page for an expanded view of the complete M5 Gas Mask assembly.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army E1R1 Dog Gas Mask
    <name>US Army E1R1 Dog Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1926 </Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Army Dogs)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-202</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-202</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-202.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $250+</price>
    <Notes>  The E1R1 Dog Gas Mask was a very early attempt to design a mask for protecting dogs in the theater of war. The E1R1 was made from stitched leather in the shape of the dogs head, with a long collar that was designed to be strapped around the dogs neck to create a seal. The muzzle piece was made from layers of gauze like material that could be soaked in a gas proof solution prior to use. The E1R1 project was short lived, and plans to design a protective mask for dogs were abandoned shortly afterword, not to be picked up again until the mid 1940s. See the DETAILS page below for more information on this exquisitely rare mask.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army E12R8 Dog Gas Mask
    <name>US Army E12R8 Dog Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1943/1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Army Dogs)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-063</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-063</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-063.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $250+</price>
    <Notes>  Prior to the standardization of the M6-12-8 Dog Gas Mask (originally designated the E43R3), the E12R8 Dog Gas Mask was designed. The shape of the mask is similar to the M6-12-8, but only one filter was used, and placed on the front of the mask. A M8 exhale valve was positioned on the bottom of the mask, directing spent air downward. The E12R8 was not used because the filter placement most likely caused refuse to get trapped in the intake slots as the dog tried to sniff the ground, thus blocking outside air. In addition, a single filter unit may not have been sufficient for the animal to breath adequately during strenuous work. The E12R8 is certainly very scarce on collector's market, as very few were ever made.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M6-12-8 Dog Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M6-12-8 Dog Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Army Dogs)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-064</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-064</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-064.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $250+</price>
    <Notes>  The M6-12-8 Dog Gas Mask (originally designated the E43R3) is certainly one of the rarest of the W.W.II US gas masks. It was designed primarily for German Shepherds and perhaps other large working dogs. The mask used a single hard plastic visor to shield the dog's eyes. Dual threaded filter discs identical to those used on the Navy NC-1 gas masks were used. A metal 'mud guard' was also attached to the filter inlets to prevent debris from clogging the air intake holes. Due to some obvious complications, the mask was never produced in significant numbers (only 1,409 were produced during the war period), and thus is quite scarce and can bring well over $1000 on the collector's market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M7-11-9 Headwound Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M7-11-9 Headwound Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1943 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Army)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-065</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-065</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-065.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $100+</price>
    <Notes>  The US Army M7 Headwound Gas Mask is another of the very scarce US W.W.II era masks. It was made of a clear plastic materiel (called Vinylite) in a hood like shape. The mask could be put over the head of a disabled soldier and then secured via several fabric straps. The mask used a M11 drum type filter canister that was painted black and screwed onto the front of the mask next to the M8 exhale valve. A carrier of the same clear plastic material was used to house the mask while not in use. The M7-11-9 was used as the Army's Headwound mask until the late 1950s, when it was replaced by the ABC-M18 Headwound Protective Mask (below).</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M13 Hospital Collective Protector Headpiece
    <name>US Army M13 Hospital Collective Protector Headpiece</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Army)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-201</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-201</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-201.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $445</price>
    <Notes>  The US Army M13 Hospital Collective Protector Headpiece is very similar to the M7-11-9 Headwound Gas Mask. The M13 used a C15 type exhale valve, and had no head straps, but was otherwise just about the same. Like the M7-11-9, the M13 was made from clear "Vinylite", which gave care givers and medics the ability to monitor head wound patients more effectively, while in a CBW environment. Due to the fragile nature and limited need for these types of masks, both the M7 and M13 are quite scarce today.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army ABC-M18 Headwound Protective Mask
    <name>US Army ABC-M18 Headwound Protective Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military (Army)</Function>
    <Refrence> US-129</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-129</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-129.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $100+</price>
    <Notes>  In the late 1950s, the ABC-M18 Headwound Protective Mask was developed to replace the M7-11-9 (above). To protect soldiers suffering from wounds that prohibited the use of a normal respirator, the M18 was designed to loosely enclose the wearer's entire head and neck, and was held in place via two elastic straps (one under each arm). The entire contraption was made of a filtering material, which eliminated the need for a bulky filter canister. When not in use, the M18 was folded flat, and stored in a tall, vinyl bag with the instructions for use printed upon it (see DETAILS).</Notes>
</type>

<type> M1 Dust Respirator
    <name>M1 Dust Respirator</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-102</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-102</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-102.jpg</pic>
    <price> $15</price>
    <Notes>  The M1 Dust respirator is a simple mask used by tank drivers and other units that were exposed to heavy amounts of dust. The mask was suspended by two elastic straps and had a small circular exhale valve in the chin area. The M1 Dust Respirator was typically worn in combination with dust goggles for maximum protection. The M1 Dust Respirator can still be found today in mint un-issued condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US M16 Civilian Defense Mask (Early Mfg.)
    <name>US M16 Civilian Defense Mask (Early Mfg.)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Protective Mask CD V-800</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1952 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-066</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-066</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-066.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $200</price>
    <Notes>  This is an early version of the CDV-800. The outlet valve is positioned at a slightly different angle than the standard issue version and has a gray rubber guard instead of the typical black guard (see below mask). Also, the outlet valve seat is made of Bakelite whereas the below version has a die-cast aluminum seat. The mask is also devoid of the circular date/manufacturer's identification marking molded into the face piece.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US M16 Civilian Defense Mask
    <name>US M16 Civilian Defense Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Protective Mask CD V-800</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1957 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-067</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-067</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-067.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $30 </price>
    <Notes>  The M16 Civilian Defense mask was designed during the Cold War era and was most likely meant to be an upgrade to the earlier W.W.II era type civilian masks. The mask used a simple face piece made of textured sheet rubber with a single plastic visor. A 60mm thread drum type canister was attached chin of the mask and an exhale valve was attached to the left side. The mask came in various sizes and was carried in an olive drab canvas bag. The M16 was made in large numbers and can still be found today in the original cardboard carton.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US CD V-805 (Early Mfg.)
    <name>US CD V-805 (Early Mfg.)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   E52R27/US M22 Civilian Defense Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. late 1950s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-068</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-068</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-068.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $350</price>
    <Notes>  The CD V-805 specimen pictured to the right is an early production CD V-805 (M22) respirator. It is quite possibly an E52R27 prototype. It's overall design is very close to the standardized model (below) but with some notable differences. First off, the plastic eye pieces are much smaller and of a slightly different shape; a feature that was most likely updated for the final version to offer a better field of view. Also, the filter padding element is ruggedly fused and several of the seams seem to be hand "melded" together. The mask also has a black elastic head harness instead of the typical gray elastic harness. In addition, the masks carrier is of an early design also. Because the mask bears no mold markings or dates, it is difficult to positively identify it. Either way, it is a scarce early production model, and not easily obtained on the collector's market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US M22 Civilian Defense Mask
    <name>US M22 Civilian Defense Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   CD V-805</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. late 1950s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-069</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-069</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-069.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $165</price>
    <Notes>  The M22 Civilian Defense mask was originally manufactured to be a lightweight, disposable, compact civilian defense respirator. Due to several developmental problems, the mask never entered full scale production, making it difficult to find today. However, most surviving examples can be found in mint un-issued condition and often in their original paper wrapper. The mask came with a transparent plastic carrier, which had the donning instructions stamped to the outside for quick and easy reference in an emergency. While the M22 is similar in design to the M28 Riot Control Agent Gas Mask, it does not have removable filter elements in the cheek, but rather a non-removable filter pad molded into the face piece.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M28 Riot Control Agent Mask
    <name>US Army M28 Riot Control Agent Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   XM28E4 Riot Control Agent Mask Grasshopper Maks</Aliases>
    <Date>   c 1968 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common/Uncommon </Frequency>
    <Country>  United States</Country>
    <Function> Military </Function>
    <Refrence> US-070</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-070</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-070.jpg</pic>
    <price> $85  </price>
    <Notes> The Army M28 Riot Control Agent Gas Mask was designed to be a lightweight and compact mask for use by soldiers who deployed tear gas into the Vietcong tunnels during the Vietnam War. The mask was carrier in a very small green pouch which could be clipped to the belt or webbing. The mask itself was designed to be neatly folded up for storage inside the carrier, making the whole package quite small. A thin but durable elastic head harness was used for suspension. Like the US M17 Field Protective Mask, the M28 was fitted with dual cheek filter elements that could be replaced after they expired. The M28 is relatively common on the surplus/collector's market and can be found in excellent condition with the carrier. </Notes>
</type>

<type> Army M10/M11/M11A1/M12 Special-Purpose Masks
    <name>Army M10/M11/M11A1/M12 Special-Purpose Masks</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   All Service Gas Mask/Special Purpose Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-071</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-071</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-071.jpg</pic>
    <price> $379</price>
    <Notes>  As early as the 1920s, Mine Safety Appliances designed the All Service Gas Mask for miners and other similar professions. The MSA All Service face piece was the basis for a multitude of different industrial protective masks manufactured well into the 1950s, and sometime during the 1940s the US military used the All Service face piece for several "Special Purpose" gas masks. They were given different designations that corresponded to their filters and the gases they protected against. The MSA All Service Gas Mask is quite common today on the collector's market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Army M20 Oxygen-Generating Breathing Apparatus
    <name>Army M20 Oxygen-Generating Breathing Apparatus</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1980s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army/Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-072</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-072</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-072.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $220</price>
    <Notes>  To fulfill the need for an oxygen generating re-breather, the US Army issued the M20 Oxygen-Generating Breathing Apparatus. This unit, like all other re-breathers used a large canister that released oxygen generated by a chemical reaction into an inflatable bladder than was worn around the chest or back. Perhaps the most interesting aspect of the M20 is that it used the familiar MSA All Service type face piece, a design that remained in use from the 1920s, well into the 1980s. The M20 was housed in a large olive-drab carrying trunk, similar to the commercial MSA re-breather units. The unit also came with several spare canisters and a black rubber hood which could be used where full body coverage was necessary. The M20 can still be found today in mint un-issued condition, but is becoming more and more difficult to find.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M14A1 Tank Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M14A1 Tank Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1960 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-073</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-073</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-073.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $115</price>
    <Notes>  After W.W.II, it was apparent that a better protective mask for tank crews was needed. This resulted in the M14 Tank Gas Mask in 1953, which was later updated and designated the M14A1 (at right). The M14A1 had no inner mask and thus was somewhat prone to fogging. The filter unit used with the M14A1 was equipped to be connected to a tanks forced air system, but could also be used outside the tank by removing the rubber connector. A microphone cord was also fitted to allow radio communications while the mask was in use inside the tank. The M14A1 is somewhat difficult to find today as it was replaced by the M14A2 and then by the more common M24/M25 series masks.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M14A2 Tank Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M14A2 Tank Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1961 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-074</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-074</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-074.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $140</price>
    <Notes>  The M14A2 was basically an upgrade to the M14A1 that included an inner nose cup to help reduce fogging. In general, the M14A2 is very similar to the later M24/M25 series mask with only a few differences. The M14A2 is quite scarce today as few were made before the switch to the M24/M25 series.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army ABC-M24 Chemical-Biological Aircraft Mask
    <name>US Army ABC-M24 Chemical-Biological Aircraft Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1962</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-075</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-075</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-075.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $250+</price>
    <Notes>  After a few modifications were made to the M14A1 Tank Mask, the US standardized the ABC-M24 Chemical- Biological Aircraft Mask. Like the M14A1, the M24 was equipped with a microphone attachment. However, the M24 used a male connector instead of the female connector used on the tank masks. This is perhaps the best way to tell the M24 apart from the M25 series. With the implementation of the M24, a inner mask was installed, which kept the mask from excessive fogging while in use. Aside from this modification, the M14A1 and the M24 are virtually identical. The M24 can still be found today on the surplus market in good used condition, but it is more common to find the M25A1 Tank Mask.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M25A1 Chemical-Biological Tank Mask
    <name>US Army M25A1 Chemical-Biological Tank Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1963 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common/Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-076</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-076</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-076.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $250+</price>
    <Notes>  Like the M24, the M25A1 Tank Mask was an upgrade to the M14A1 Tank Mask. It used the same basic features found on the M24, however a female microphone connector was used to allow the mask to be linked to the tank's radio communications system. The M25A1 also had a special filter unit that could be attached to the tanks forced air system. The M25A1 was also accompanied by a butyl rubber hood and a tinted visor overlay. The M25A1 is quite common today and can still be found in excellent condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M17 Gas Mask (Early Mfg.)
    <name>US Army M17 Gas Mask (Early Mfg.)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1959 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-077</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-077</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-077.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $315</price>
    <Notes>  In effort to solve some of the problems found with the M9 series masks, the Army began work on a new lightweight mask that offered more comfort and compactness, while maintaining a high level of protection. The results were standardized the M17 Field Protective Gas Mask in 1959. The M17 went on to be another of the most successful masks ever made, as it was copied by at least four other countries. The mask pictured at right, was most likely manufactured very early on, and is possibly a final prototype for the M17. The US Chemical Warfare Service insignia was molded into the front of the face piece, a feature not found on the standardized version.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army XM27 (Silicone)
    <name>US Army XM27 (Silicone)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1966 </Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-200</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-200</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-200.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price? $250+</price>
    <Notes>  This particular mask was made in 1966, from transparent silicone. It was an experimental design based on the M17. The mask was designed to be folded and stored in a very small carrier, similar to the XM28 concept. Originally, the silicone would have been completely transparent, but silicone yellows over time, giving this mask the amber appearance. These maskks are extremely rare today, as few were likely made.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M17 Field Protective Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M17 Field Protective Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1959 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-078</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-078</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-078.jpg</pic>
    <price> $55</price>
    <Notes>  At right, the common M17 series gas mask is pictured. This mask was designed to be an upgrade to the successful M9 series gas mask. The M17 eliminated the need for a bulky external filter canister, which also made the mask more suitable for both left and right handed soldiers. The mask used two "pork-chop" filter elements that were held in cheek pockets on either side of the mask. The cheek filters proved to be lightweight and efficient in the field. A voice-mitter was also implemented and from this point forward, was a standard feature on all US masks to follow. The M17 was also issued with a protective butyl rubber hood and eye lens outserts. The M17 was used during the Vietnam war, frequently by law enforcement during anti-war protests in the US. The M17 was manufactured in large numbers, and can easily be found today on the surplus market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M17A1/M17A2 Field Protective Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M17A1/M17A2 Field Protective Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1966 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-079</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-079</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-079.jpg</pic>
    <price> $130</price>
    <Notes>  In 1966, a drinking tube was added to the M17 gas mask, which resulted in the M17A1 Field Protective Gas Mask. In addition, the M17A1 was also issued with a resuscitation tube, which could be used to deliver CPR between two masked soldiers. In 1983, the M17A1 was changed to the M17A2, after an extra small size was introduced. Overall however, there is no difference between the M17A1 and M17A2. Like the earlier M17 series, the M17A1 and M17A2 was also issued with a protective butyl hood and eye lens outserts. The M17A2 is best known for it's heavy use in the Gulf War. When the struggle in the Middle-East broke out, the M17A2 was still the Army's standard mask. Here is where the M17A2 was really put to the test. It was a result of this war that lead to the development of yet an even better protective mask. The M17A2 was manufactured in large numbers and can be found readily on the surplus market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M17A1/M17A2 Field Protective Gas Mask
    <name>US Army M17A1/M17A2 Field Protective Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1966 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-146</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-146</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-146.jpg</pic>
    <price> $130</price>
    <Notes>  This rare version of the M17A2 was equipped with a special microphone housing on the front of the mask. This mask was most likely used with a microphone and head-set for vehicle crew members. The remaining component of the mask are identical to the standard issue M17A2.</Notes>
</type>

<type> XM-29
    <name>XM-29</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. mid 1970s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-136</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-136</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-136.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $150+</price>
    <Notes>  The XM-29 series of masks were experimental designs that eventually lead to the standardization of the MCU-2/P (below). Originally, there were four types built, one each for combat, armor, aviation and special purpose. They all used a single, integrated lens made from transparent silicone rubber. However, it was found that the lens coating was problematic, and prone to excessive scratching. These problems lead to further experimentation and the development of the XM-30 series. XM-29 masks are very rare today, as few were made and many discarded.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy/Air Force MCU-2/P Chemical-Biological Mask (Scott)
    <name>US Navy/Air Force MCU-2/P Chemical-Biological Mask (Scott)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1980s</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Navy/AirForce</Function>
    <Refrence> US-080</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-080</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-080.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $220</price>
    <Notes>  The MCU-2/P was the result of much experimentation that took place during the 1970s. Originally designated the XM30, the MCU-2/P was manufactured entirely of translucent silicone rubber with a large plastic visor. This feature gave the mask an excellent field of view. The mask also implemented the use of a left or right side filter inlet assembly and voice-mitter. The MCU-2/P also made use of a drinking tube like the M17A1/A2 series masks. Problems with the use of silicone rubber resulted in the dropping of the XM30 project by the Army, however, the US Air Force liked the design and standardized the mask the MCU-2/P (Mask, Chemical Uniform-2/P). At right, an early version of the MCU-2/P made by Scott Aviation is pictured. This version, made entirely of silicone rubber, is not as common as the later gray silicone versions.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy/Air Force MCU-2/P Chemical-Biological Mask
    <name>US Navy/Air Force MCU-2/P Chemical-Biological Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1980s</Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Navy/AirForce</Function>
    <Refrence> US-081</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-081</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-081.jpg</pic>
    <price> $120</price>
    <Notes>  After standardization, the MCU-2/P was manufactured in large numbers using gray silicone rubber. The mask also came issued with a protective butyl hood that was worn over the head, neck and upper shoulders. The MCU-2/P was used extensively during the Gulf War along side the M17A2. The MCU-2/P was later upgraded to the MCU-2A/P when a microphone connector was added to the voice-mitter assembly. While the MCU-2/P is quite common on the surplus market, the later MCU-2A/P seems to be more abundant.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Navy/Air Force MCU-2A/P Chemical-Biological Mask
    <name>US Navy/Air Force MCU-2A/P Chemical-Biological Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1980s </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Navy/AirForce</Function>
    <Refrence> US-082</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-082</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-082.jpg</pic>
    <price> $600</price>
    <Notes>  Under a new contract, the MCU-2A/P upgrade was manufactured by ILC and MSA. The voice-mitter assembly was reworked to incorporate a female microphone connector. This is the easiest way to tell the MCU-2/P from the MCU-2A/P. Both used the same carrier and protective butyl hood. Toward the end of the Gulf War, the MCU series masks were phased out and replaced by the M40 series. The MCU-2A/P is for some reason more common on the surplus market than the earlier MCU-2/P.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army XM40 Field Protective Mask (ILC/Dover)
    <name>US Army XM40 Field Protective Mask (ILC/Dover)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1980s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-083</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-083</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-083.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $475</price>
    <Notes>  This early M40 prototype is quite unusual when compared to other M40 prototypes. It's construction is somewhat loose, and obviously an example design. Quite different from the final M40 design, this mask uses an entirely different drinking tube system and voice-mitter assembly. When examining the the development of modern US Army gas masks, the evolution can be clearly seen when prototype examples are compared. This mask is definitely scarce on the collector's market, for obvious reasons.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army XM40 Field Protective Mask (ILC/Dover)
    <name>US Army XM40 Field Protective Mask (ILC/Dover)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1980s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-084</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-084</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-084.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $475</price>
    <Notes>  This M40 prototype, made by ILC/DOVER, uses a drinking tube/voice-mitter assembly that is very similar to the earlier M17A2 mask. The XM42 also used this design, but incorporated a microphone connection wire that protruded from the voice-mitter area. The evolution from the M17 to the M40 can be clearly seen in the XM40. This mask is definitely scarce on the collector's market, for obvious reasons.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M40 Field Protective Mask
    <name>US Army M40 Field Protective Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1987 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-085</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-085</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-085.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $80 </price>
    <Notes>  After years of experimentation, the M40 series was born. The M40 Field Protective Mask was made of silicone rubber, despite several known issues with silicon concerning its protective integrity when exposed to mustard gas and other similar agents. For this reason it was also issued with a protective Butyl rubber hood. The M40 was later updated in 1992 and designated the M40A1. The M40 is now readily available on the surplus market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M40A1 Field Protective Mask
    <name>US Army M40A1 Field Protective Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1992 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-086</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-086</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-086.jpg</pic>
    <price> $200</price>
    <Notes>  In 1992, the M40 series was reworked with a better nose cup and a new Butyl protective hood. The new hood required a rubber "second skin" that covered the entire mask's face piece This new design offered a higher level of protection against penetrating NBC agents and also made it easier to don the protective hood. The M40A1 is not as plentiful on the surplus market as few have been released as surplus.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M40A2 Field Protective Mask
    <name>US Army M40A2 Field Protective Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   late c. 1990s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-087</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-087</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-087.jpg</pic>
    <price> $100</price>
    <Notes>  Sometime in the late 1990s, the M40A1 was upgraded with a few new features to create the M40A2. The M42A1 was also similarly updated with a new second skin which had a broader lever of protection. Both the M40A2 and the M42A2 are still in use and not yet very common on the surplus market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M42 Armored Vehicle Protective Mask
    <name>US Army M42 Armored Vehicle Protective Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1987 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-088</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-088</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-088.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $195</price>
    <Notes>  With the M40 Field Protective Mask, the M42 Armored Vehicle Protective Mask was issued. The mask's face piece is more or less identical to the M40, but incorporated a microphone hook up for use inside tanks. The M42 also used a fixed breathing tube that attached to a standard C2 filter canister. When in use, the filter could be connected to the vehicles forced air system via a plastic and metal connector piece that is normally housed in the mask's carrier. The M42 was later updated and designated the M42A1. For some reason, the M42 is not as easy to find on the surplus market.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M42A1 Armored Vehicle Protective Mask
    <name>US Army M42A1 Armored Vehicle Protective Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1992 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-089</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-089</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-089.jpg</pic>
    <price> $190</price>
    <Notes>  In 1992, the M42 was updated to incorporate a wider detachable breathing tube, a better nose cup and a new Butyl hood using the "second skin" system. The mask was now designated the M42A1. Later, in 1995, the mask was reworked again to have a simplified detachable microphone, a better second skin and a larger carrier. This version was designated the M42A2. Both versions are somewhat difficult to come by on the surplus market as they are still in use today.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M43 Type I NBC Aircrew Respirator
    <name>US Army M43 Type I NBC Aircrew Respirator</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1986 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-090</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-090</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-090.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $150+</price>
    <Notes>  Due to the need for a protective mask for AH-64 Apache helicopter pilots, the M43 Type I NBC Aircrew Respirator was designed. This mask used a sophisticated system that incorporated forced air, a drinking tube, an integrated Butyl hood and the M171/AIC microphone. The Type I also had a special notched eye piece that could be used with the AH-64 Integrated Helmet and Display Sighting System (IHADSS). While the whole setup is quite bulky, it provides the protection needed for the pilot. The M43 was later significantly updated and designated the M48. Both M43 types are still quite scarce on the surplus market as few were released into the public.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M43 Type II NBC Aircrew Respirator
    <name>US Army M43 Type II NBC Aircrew Respirator</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1986 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-091</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-091</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-091.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $150+</price>
    <Notes>  To accommodate other aircrew personnel, the M43 Type II was issued. This mask was more or less identical to the M43 Type I, but it did not have the special notched eye piece and used the M133/U microphone. The M43 was later significantly updated and designated the M48. Both M43 types are still quite scarce on the surplus market as few were released into the public.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army XM44 NBC Respirator
    <name>US Army XM44 NBC Respirator</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1990s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-092</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-092</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-092.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $250+</price>
    <Notes>  The US Army XM44 is an experimental mask made during the development of the M45 series masks. It used a sleek, comfortable design and came equipped with a protective butyl hood. When comparing the XM44 with the final M45 mask, the evolution can be clearly seen. The XM44 is very scarce on the surplus market as few were released into the public.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M45 NBC Respirator
    <name>US Army M45 NBC Respirator</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1990s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-093</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-093</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-093.jpg</pic>
    <price> $150</price>
    <Notes>  The M45 was developed to replace the M40 series masks for both infantry and armored vehicle crews. The mask may have also been used as a replacement for the M43 series on helicopters. Like the earlier M40 series, the M45 came equipped with a drinking mechanism, speech amplifier, and the ability to attach a C2A1 filter canister to either the left or right side of the mask. The M45 also used a specially fitted, butyl rubber hood and eye lens outserts. The mask was issued it a standard olive drab carrier with or without a breathing hose, depending on intended use. It is possible that the infantry version of the M45 did not come with a microphone attachment. The M45 is quite scarce on the surplus market as it was later phased out by the JSGPM (XM50) project.</Notes>
</type>

<type> US Army M45 NBC Respirator
    <name>US Army M45 NBC Respirator</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1990s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Army</Function>
    <Refrence> US-300</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-300</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-300.jpg</pic>
    <price> $150</price>
    <Notes>  The M45 pictured to the right is identical to the above mask, but has the long rubber breathing hose attached. The hose was designed very similarly to the earlier M42A2.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Kops Tear Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Law Enforcement</Function>
    <Refrence> US-094</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-094</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-094.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $150+</price>
    <Notes>  This mask, constructed using a Kops type face piece, was issued as a riot control agent mask for use by police and other law enforcement organizations. This mask is among the many early US non-combatant masks based directly on designs that were also adopted by the US military.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Kops Industrial Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-095</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-095</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-095.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $45 </price>
    <Notes>  This mask, constructed using a Kops type face piece, was used for industrial applications. The example pictured to the right used a canister Type GME-1 for protection against acid gases and organic vapors.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Kops Rebreather</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial/Navy</Function>
    <Refrence> US-096</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-096</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-096.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $150+</price>
    <Notes>  This early rebreather was most likely used by the mining industry, but may have also been used by the US Navy as one of their earliest rebreathers. The face piece is of the Kops design, and came with a heavy rebreather unit that was worn around the neck. A fabricized rubber bladder was used as the rebreather bag which was attached to the rebreather device and tank (see DETAILS).</Notes>
</type>

<type> Bullard All Service Mask
    <name>Bullard All Service Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. late 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-097</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-097</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-097.jpg</pic>
    <price> $150</price>
    <Notes>  This early industrial mask was made by the E.D. Bullard company in the 1930s. This particular example was most likely used as a supplied air respirator, however the face piece for this mask was used for several different industrial protective masks.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Pulmosan Respirator GR-2 10
    <name>Pulmosan Respirator GR-2 10</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-100</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-100</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-100.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $100+</price>
    <Notes>  This early industrial mask was most likely used for protection against dust or spray, as it used a simple design of molded sheet rubber which only covered the wearers face. A small filter was fixed on the front of the mask and a flapper type exhale valve was positioned in the chin area.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-101</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-101</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-101.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $100+</price>
    <Notes>  This mask, also manufactured by Pulmosan Safety, is another early industrial mask which was also looked at by the US military. The mask's face piece was the basis for the US E28R37 Airplane Pilot's Gas Mask and also the E32R35 Training Gas Mask.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. mid 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-195</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-195</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-195.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $100+</price>
    <Notes>  This mask is another early industrial respirator manufactured by Pulmosan Safety. Like the above mask, it used a molded rubber face piece with a filter mounted in the chin position and an exhale valve on the front. Like most other early Pulmosan industrial gas masks, this type is also quite rare today.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Comfo Respirator
    <name>Comfo Respirator</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Common/Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States
</Country>
    <Function>  Industrial/Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-103</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-103</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-103.jpg</pic>
    <price> $30</price>
    <Notes>  The Comfo respirator was a commonly used half mask that was also adopted for use by the US military as an early dust mask. The mask covered the wearers nose and mouth and filtered heavy particles from the air via two circular felt lined filters mounted on either cheek. The mask also had a flapper type exhale valve in the chin position. Comfo Respirators can still be found today in mint un-issued condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-104</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-104</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-104.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $100+</price>
    <Notes>  This mask is most likely another type of Comfo Respirator for protection while sand blasting or some other similar task. The filters and flapper type exhale valve are the same as the above mask.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Cover's Automatic Respirator
    <name>Cover's Automatic Respirator</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-196</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-196</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-196.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $100+</price>
    <Notes>  This small half-mask is interesting as it may have been used for both industrial and early military applications. This simple mask used a filter made from a natural sponge, which could be soaked in anti-gas solution prior to use. A small exhale check valve was also present on the top left side of the mask. This mask was typically worn with a pair of protective Cover's goggles.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-105</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-105</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-105.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $40 </price>
    <Notes>  This mask, made by Willson, is an early industrial mask to protect against Ammonia and other similar industrial hazards. This mask used a face piece design similar to the US Army's M2 face piece. Several masks made by Willson during the WWII era used face pieces that closely resembled many military types.</Notes>
</type>

<type> C.E.S.CO Fume Mask
    <name>C.E.S.CO Fume Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-106</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-106</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-106.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $75+</price>
    <Notes>  The C.E.S.CO (Chicago Eye Shield Company) Fume mask is a simple mask designed to protect against dusts, fumes and other industrial hazards. The mask used a small, removable filter canister that was housed in a compartment on the front of the mask.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-107</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-107</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-107.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $75+</price>
    <Notes>  This industrial protective mask was made by Burell and used with a MSA Type GMD-SS canister for use against ammonia, dusts, mists and fogs. This face piece was also used as the basis for the US Army/Navy Mark I Diaphragm Mask, however the military version used a fabricized rubber face piece instead. The design of the mask is otherwise almost identical.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-108</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-108</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-108.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $75+</price>
    <Notes>  This mask, also made by the Burell company was another industrial mask for use against ammonia and other industrial hazards. The mask used a rubber face piece and head harness, with an exhale valve in front very similar to the "Connel" type exhale valves used with many military masks from this time.</Notes>
</type>

<type> MSA Abrasives Mask
    <name>MSA Abrasives Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial/Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-109</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-109</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-109.jpg</pic>
    <price> $165</price>
    <Notes>  This MSA Abrasives mask was designed for use during sand blasting and other similar activities. The mask had a special glass visor that could be closed for extra protection against abrasive over-spray (roll-over image at right) and was most likely always used with a supplied air system.</Notes>
</type>

<type> LEECO No. 45 Gas Mask
    <name>LEECO No. 45 Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Law Enforcement</Function>
    <Refrence> US-110</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-110</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-110.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $45 </price>
    <Notes>  This mask is another gas mask made by LEECO (Lake Erie Chemical Company) for use against tear gas and nauseating gas. The mask was made from gray rubber and featured a button style exhale valve on the left side of the face piece.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Pulmosan AL 170 Airline Mask
    <name>Pulmosan AL 170 Airline Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-111</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-111</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-111.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $45 </price>
    <Notes>  The Pulmosan AL 170 Airline Mask used a face piece identical to the LEECO No. 45 Gas Mask (above). This mask was used with a supplied air system aboard aircrafts.</Notes>
</type>

<type> ACME Full Vision Gas Mask
    <name>ACME Full Vision Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-112</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-112</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-112.jpg</pic>
    <price> $40</price>
    <Notes>  The ACME Full Vision gas mask was used as the basic for many different industrial masks and also for some gas masks used for protection against military agents (see below). The mask's face piece was constructed with two large glass windows giving the wearer and excellent field of view. The mask was used with both a hose and filter box as well as with a filter canister attached directly to the face piece.</Notes>
</type>

<type> ACME Full Vision Gas Mask
    <name>ACME Full Vision Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-113</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-113</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-113.jpg</pic>
    <price> $40</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the ACME Full Vision Gas Mask came equipped with a Chin Style 15-M filter canister designated for protection against "warfare gases, vapors and smokes". This mask may have been adopted for use by the US military at some point, but was most likely just a commercially sold mask that could be used with a special canister for warfare agents.</Notes>
</type>

<type> MSA All Service Gas Mask
    <name>MSA All Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1920s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-119</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-119</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-119.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $85 </price>
    <Notes>  The All Service Gas Mask was first introduced by Mine Safety Appliances in the 1920s. The example pictured at right is an early example that used a fabric and leather head harness. The All Service design was very successful, and went on to be used for several decades for many different industrial applications, as well for the US military as a special purpose mask. The All Service face piece was also used for many different rebreather units and tear gas masks.</Notes>
</type>

<type> MSA All Service Gas Mask
    <name>MSA All Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-118</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-118</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-118.jpg</pic>
    <price> $85</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the All Service Gas Mask is a later example that used a rubber head harness instead of the early fabric and leather type.</Notes>
</type>

<type> MSA All Service Gas Mask
    <name>MSA All Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-120</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-120</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-120.jpg</pic>
    <price> $85</price>
    <Notes>  This rare version of the MSA All Service Gas Mask was entirely from white rubber. This mask may have been used as a special purpose mask where it needed to be easily separated from other masks made from the standard black rubber.</Notes>
</type>

<type> MSA All Service Gas Mask
    <name>MSA All Service Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-121</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-121</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-121.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $85</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the MSA All Service Gas Mask was equipped with a circular speech diaphragm on the front of the mask. Overall the mask was identical to the regular All Service mask. This face piece type was also commonly used with several MSA rebreather units.</Notes>
</type>

<type> MSA Riot Mask
    <name>MSA Riot Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Law Enforcement</Function>
    <Refrence> US-115</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-115</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-115.jpg</pic>
    <price> $45</price>
    <Notes>  This mask, also made by MSA, is a tear gas mask based on the MSA All Service Face Piece. The mask used a cylindrical filter canister that was housed in a rubber cup on the front of the mask. Two circular exhale valves were also present on either side of the mask.</Notes>
</type>

<type> MSA Riot Mask
    <name>MSA Riot Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Law Enforcement</Function>
    <Refrence> US-117</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-117</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-117.jpg</pic>
    <price> $45</price>
    <Notes>  This mask is basically identical to the above version, but was equipped with a large speech diaphragm on the front.</Notes>
</type>

<type> MSA Riot Mask
    <name>MSA Riot Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Law Enforcement</Function>
    <Refrence> US-116</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-116</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-116.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $30 </price>
    <Notes>  This mask is another riot control mask based on the common MSA All Service face piece. However this version used a different assembly for attaching filter canisters. This mask was most likely an updated version of the above two riot control masks.</Notes>
</type>

<type> MSA Chemox Oxygen Breathing Apparatus
    <name>MSA Chemox Oxygen Breathing Apparatus</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-188</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-188</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-188.jpg</pic>
    <price> $200</price>
    <Notes>  The MSA Chemox Oxygen Breathing Apparatus was a commonly used rebreather for industrial applications. The unit was used with the MSA All Service Face Piece and came in a large wooden trunk, similar to most other US made rebreather units during this time (see DETAILS).</Notes>
</type>

<type> Davis Gas Mask
    <name>Davis Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-123</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-123</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-123.jpg</pic>
    <price> $150</price>
    <Notes>  This early Davis gas mask was used with an ammonia filter and was made entirely from orange colored rubber, as with many Davis Gas Mask from this time period. This particular mask is interesting because its face piece closely resembles the US Army M2 type face piece.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Davis Gas Mask Type M-1
    <name>Davis Gas Mask Type M-1</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Davis Type M Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-124</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-124</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-124.jpg</pic>
    <price> $150</price>
    <Notes>  This early Davis gas mask was another brightly colored industrial mask. This mask came equipped with a Victor type filter canister.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1957 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Law Enforcement</Function>
    <Refrence> US-133</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-133</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-133.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $100</price>
    <Notes>  This interesting mask dates from the late 1950s and was made by Mine Safety Appliances. It is most likely a commercial smoke mask for flight crews. The mask was intended to be used with a forced air supply system, which was typically found on planes and inside armored vehicles. Circular exhale valves are present on either side of the mask, and a microphone was also integrated in place of a speech diaphragm. This mask was most likely examined for use by the US military, but was never put into pro ductio n.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-122</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-122</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-122.jpg</pic>
    <price> $175</price>
    <Notes>  This mask, also made by Mine Safety Appliances, was manufactured around the same time as the above mask. It used a green rubber face piece with two plastic eye pieces and dual filter canisters very similar to the US Navy Diaphragm Gas Mask, Mark V (US-049). A combination exhale valve/speech diaphragm was positioned on the front of this mask. This mask was most likely a commerically used mask to protect against industrial hazards.</Notes>
</type>

<type> MSA All Service Gas Mask Model S
    <name>MSA All Service Gas Mask Model S</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1970s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-174</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-174</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-174.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $30 </price>
    <Notes>  The MSA All Service Gas Mask Model S was a standard MSA face piece used with various types of protective respirators and tear gas masks during the 1970s. It used a large clear visor and could be used with a chin mounter filter canister or a filter canister and hose tube.</Notes>
</type>

<type> LECCO Full-View Tear Gas Mask
    <name>LECCO Full-View Tear Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Law Enforcement</Function>
    <Refrence> US-098</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-098</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-098.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $30 </price>
    <Notes>  This mask was designed with a large plastic one piece visor and was most likely used by police and other law enforcement personnel for use against tear gas. The face piece was made by Mine Safety Appliances and the filter was made by LECCO (Lake Erie Chemical Company).</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial/Law Enforcement</Function>
    <Refrence> US-099</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-099</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-099.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $30 </price>
    <Notes>  This mask is very similar to the above mask, but was most likely used for industrial protection. As with many commercially available masks, they were used for various applications, and were sold with filters for specific uses. This mask was most likely manufactured by Willson.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1970s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-114</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-114</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-114.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $50</price>
    <Notes>  This mask is a modern type MSA respirator used with a battery powered, forced air filter pack. This type of system helped force filtered air into the mask which reduced breathing resistance and helped keep the wearer cool. A similar concept was employed by the US military for use with some tank masks and helicopter masks.</Notes>
</type>

<type> MSA Advantage 1000
    <name>MSA Advantage 1000</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1990s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Law Enforcement</Function>
    <Refrence> US-125</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-125</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-125.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $50 </price>
    <Notes>  This modern MSA mask was obviously based on the same design as the US Navy MCU-2/P, and was used mainly by police and corrections officers, as well as SWAT teams. The mask was typically equipped with filters for tear gases and other riot control agents. It is very similar to the MSA Millenium Mask.</Notes>
</type>

<type> MCU-1/P
    <name>MCU-1/P</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1980s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-126</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-126</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-126.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $35 </price>
    <Notes>  The Scott MCU-1/P is a commercially available mask that used a full face shield and a fabric head net for suspension. This mask may have been the predecessor to the Navy's MCU-2/P, however there is not much of a resemblance.</Notes>
</type>
<type>
    <name>Cover Smoke Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>Smoke Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>c. 1915</Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial/Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-401-GL</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-401-GL</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-401-GL.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $35 </price>
    <Notes> This mask when paired with the goggles is allegedly the first American mask in World War I, before the adoption of
                the French M2 or Enligsh small box repirator. The mask alone was originally manufactured by Cover for
                industrial use without the attached goggles. </Notes>
</type>
<type>
    <name>XM-28 Airforce</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>'Grasshopper'</Aliases>
    <Date>c. 1975</Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function> Military</Function>
    <Refrence> US-402-GL</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-402-GL</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-402-GL.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $100+ </price>
    <Notes> Variation on the M28 riot control mask intended for helicopter pilots. Head straps are removed in order for
              pilot's helmet to fit. Addtional straps areadded to the front to attach to the helmet. A plastic renforcing
                snout was added so the mask could be tied down to ensure a good fit</Notes>
</type>
<type>
    <name>Health Gaurd</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases></Aliases>
    <Date>c. 1930</Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function> Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-403-GL</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-403-GL</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-403-GL.jpg</pic>
    <price>  ??? </price>
    <Notes> Early repirator mask manufactured by Cesco. Uses corregated hose to connect to a compressor
    . Indtended for an unkown industrial or mining purpose.</Notes>
</type><type>
    <name>Fearnot Respirator</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases></Aliases>
    <Date>c. 1925</Date>
    <Frequency> Very Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function> Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> US-400-GL</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-400-GL</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-400-GL.jpg</pic>
    <price>  ??? </price>
    <Notes> Respirator with attached goggles manufactured by Pulmosan company. Intended
                for industrial use.</Notes>
</type><type>
    <name>Pulmosan Junior Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>No. 1700 Full Face Mask</Aliases>
    <Date>c. 1950</Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function> Industrial/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> US-404-GL</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-404-GL</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-404-GL.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $20-35 </price>
    <Notes> Civil/Industrial mask manufactured by Pulmosen Inc. Uses snout type mask will proprietary filter.
                Small size and production time may indicate it was marketed to take advantage of the nuclear scares in the 1950s.</Notes>
</type>
<type>
    <name>Unknown MSA Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases></Aliases>
    <Date>c. 1930</Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  United States </Country>
    <Function> Industrial/Civil Defense</Function>
    <Refrence> US-405-GL</Refrence>
    <Ref>US-405-GL</Ref>
    <pic>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/14570796/Images/US-405-GL.jpg</pic>
    <price>  ??? </price>
    <Notes> Unkown MSA branded. Uses civil defense style filter and carrier. May have been a prototype civil defense mask or for industrial use.</Notes>
</type></masks>