<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
 <?xml-stylesheet href="PageLayout.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?> <masks><type> countriesGermany
        <name>Germany </name>
        <Translation>Federal Republic of Germany</Translation>
        <Aliases>  Russia</Aliases>
        <Date> Date for Masks: 1917 - 1970s </Date>
        <Frequency>  Uncommon </Frequency>
        <Country>Capital: Berlin </Country>
        <Function> Military/Civilian/Industrial </Function>
        <Refrence> GE-???</Refrence>
        <Ref> GE </Ref>
        <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/flagGermany.jpg</pic>
        <price>Currency: Euro</price>
            <Notes> The territory of Germany covers an area of 357,021 km2 and is influenced by a temperate seasonal climate. With 81.8 million inhabitants, it is the most populous member state of the European Union. The assassination of Austria's crown prince on 28 June 1914 triggered World War I. Germany, as part of the unsuccessful Central Powers, suffered defeat against the Allied Powers in one of the bloodiest conflicts of all time. An estimated two million German soldiers died in World War I. The German Revolution broke out in November 1918, and Emperor William II and all German ruling princes abdicated. An armistice putting an end to the war was signed on 11 November, and Germany was forced to sign the Treaty of Versailles in June 1919. Its negotiation,After the proclamation of the Weimar Republic in 1918 the Third Reich followed in 1933. The period was marked by a dictatorship and the initiation of World War II. After 1945, Germany was divided by allied occupation, and evolved into two states, East Germany and West Germany. In 1990 Germany was reunified. West Germany was a founding member of the European Community in 1957, which became the EU in 1993.</Notes>
    </type>

<type> Gummischutzmaske
    <name>Gummischutzmaske</name>
    <Translation> Rubber Protective Mask 1915</Translation>
    <Aliases>   GM15</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1915 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-001</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-001</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-001.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $325</price>
    <Notes>  The German Gummischutzmaske was designed early on during WWI to protect against Allied gas attacks. The mask consisted of a simple face piece made of a rubberized material with a filter canister mounted in the snout position. There was no exhale valve present, which meant expired air had to be pushed out through the sides of the mask or back through the filter canister. This feature made the mask prone to fogging. So, like the British Small Box Respirator, the Gummischutzmaske was designed to give the wearer the ability to wipe condensation from the eye pieces without removing the mask. This was accomplished by using a finger to push the face piece material in and underneath the eye pieces on the inside of the mask to wipe free the moisture. Another interesting feature of this early mask was the head harness. Instead of elastic, the head harness was adjusted via several straps made from crinkled fabric and small metal springs.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Lederschutzmaske
    <name>Lederschutzmaske</name>
    <Translation> Leather Protective Mask 1917</Translation>
    <Aliases>   GM17</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1917 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-002</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-002</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-002.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $240</price>
    <Notes>  After both sides began to use chemical weapons during WWI, Germany developed a new mask with more protective capabilities. The material chosen was leather, which could be treated to neutralize the current gases being used at the time. A small filter canister fixed in the snout position was still used, as was a small metal carrying canister. The celluloid eye pieces were reinforced with additional metal frame on the inside of the mask similarly to the French A.R.S. artillery model. Like the Gummischutzmaske, the Lederschutzmaske GM17 did not have an exhale valve. However, a later version of the GM17 was updated with a small exhale valve on the side of the face piece. The Lederschutzmaske GM17 was made in quite significant numbers, making it one of the more easily found WWI gas masks today.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Lederschutzmaske
    <name>Lederschutzmaske</name>
    <Translation> Leather Protective Mask 1917</Translation>
    <Aliases>   GM17</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1917 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-003</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-003</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-003.jpg</pic>
    <price> $240</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the Lederschutzmaske was modified to incorporate a small metal exhale valve on the left side of the face piece. It was also issued with an updated FE37 filter and a larger metal carrying canister. Like the original Lederschutzmaske, this version also used a piece of string attached to the filter inlet assembly and the top of the head harness to help support the weight of the filter (missing from the above example). This version also lacks the reinforced eye piece frames.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Lederschutzmaske
    <name>Lederschutzmaske</name>
    <Translation> Leather Protective Mask 1918</Translation>
    <Aliases>   GM18</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1918 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-004</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-004</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-004.jpg</pic>
    <price> $240</price>
    <Notes>  The Lederschutzmaske GM18 appears to be very similar to the GM17 at a glance. However, the GM18 was made with different eye piece frames and a broader support band instead of the formerly used piece of string (see above). A metal exhale valve was still used as was the FE37 type filter canister. The metal carrying canister is also slightly different.</Notes>
</type>

<type> GM-24
    <name>GM-24</name>
    <Translation> Army Gas Mask 1924</Translation>
    <Aliases>   Heeresgasmaske 1924</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1920s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-037</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-037</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-037.jpg</pic>
    <price>$ 175</price>
    <Notes>  The GM-24 is an important transitional development in German gas mask evolution. It was a near total departure from the old WWI design, particularly considering the fact that a long breathing hose was used with a large filter instead of a small filter mounted in the chin position. However, this setup did not last long, as the GM-30 (see below) design reverted back to mounting a smaller filter directly to the face piece within the same decade. It is possible that the use of a breathing tube and larger filter had mostly to do with an increasing amount of different chemical agents that the mask needed to protect against. The face piece of the GM-24 is very similar in overall appearance to the later GM-30, which obviously was derived directly from the GM-24 design. GM-24 gas masks are now very scarce and difficult to find in good complete condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> GM-30
    <name>GM-30</name>
    <Translation> Gas Mask 1930</Translation>
    <Aliases>   S-Maske</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-005</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-005</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-005.jpg</pic>
    <price>$ 110</price>
    <Notes>  The German GM-30 is a very important gas mask from a development point of view. The style of the GM-30 was used as a basis for several different gas masks made in Germany throughout WWII, as well as several other European countries. However influential the GM-30 was, its roots were still based in the earlier GM-24, which used a hose tube and a large filter. The GM-30 was typically carried and slung in in a tall metal canister. The GM-30's exhale valve was later updated to incorporate a protective cover (see below). It might also be noted that there are several variants of the GM-30 with different paint colors and canvas colors. The version pictured to the right was most likely a civilian model or an export model. The civilian version of the GM-30 was referred to as the S-Maske. The GM-30 was later updated and re-designated the GM-38 (see below).</Notes>
</type>

<type> GM-30
    <name>GM-30</name>
    <Translation> Gas Mask 1930</Translation>
    <Aliases>   S-Maske</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-006</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-006</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-006.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $110</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the GM-30 varies from the above version in canvas color and paint color. The inlet/outlet assembly is also different from the above version. The different paint colors may have represented the function of the mask, and/or the manufacturing period.</Notes>
</type>

<type> GM-30 (with microphone adapter)
    <name>GM-30 (with microphone adapter)</name>
    <Translation>Gas Mask 1930 </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-007</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-007</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-007.jpg</pic>
    <price> $145</price>
    <Notes>  This version of the GM-30 had an extra inlet incorporated into the right side of the face piece for use by microphone operators. A threaded cap was attached to the inlet by a small chain, and was removed when the microphone was attached.</Notes>
</type>

<type> GM-38
    <name>GM-38</name>
    <Translation>Gas Mask 1938 </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1938 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-008</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-008</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-008.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $138</price>
    <Notes>  The GM-38 is basically just an upgraded GM-30. The GM-38's face piece was made entirely from rubber, which was most likely a move to protect against newly discovered chemical agents that could penetrate other materials.</Notes>
</type>

<type> GM-38
    <name>GM-38</name>
    <Translation> Gas Mask 1938</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1938 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-009</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-009</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-009.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $100</price>
    <Notes>  The GM-38 is basically just an upgraded GM-30. The GM-38's face piece was made entirely from rubber, which was most likely a move to protect against newly discovered chemical agents that could penetrate other materials.</Notes>
</type>

<type> GM-44
    <name>GM-44</name>
    <Translation> Gas Mask 1944</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-010</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-010</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-010.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $210</price>
    <Notes>  This particular mask is very similar in design to the GM-38, but the overall construction is quite different. The mask came in a fabric carrier instead of the typical canister and may have been used by the Luftwaffe during the final months of the war. The example pictured to the right is dated 1944.</Notes>
</type>

<type> VM-37 (Volksgasmaske 37)
    <name>VM-37 (Volksgasmaske 37)</name>
    <Translation> People's Gas Mask 1937</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1937 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common/Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-011</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-011</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-011.jpg</pic>
    <price> $50</price>
    <Notes>  The German VM-37 is a very common WWII era German civilian mask that was made using the "helmet" style face piece that encapsulated the wearers entire head. There were at least two different versions of this mask, one for civilians and one for civil defense. One version of the mask has a rubber adjusting strap on the back to make the mask tighter if the fit is too loose. The other version is devoid of the rear neck strap (see below).</Notes>
</type>

<type> VM-37 (Volksgasmaske 37)
    <name>VM-37 (Volksgasmaske 37)</name>
    <Translation> People's Gas Mask 1937</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1937 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common/Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany</Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-012</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-012</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-012.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $40 </price>
    <Notes>  The German VM-37 is a very common WWII era German civilian mask that was made using the "helmet" style face piece that encapsulated the wearers entire head. There were at least two different versions of this mask, one for civilians and one for civil defense. One version of the mask has a rubber adjusting strap on the back to make the mask tighter if the fit is too loose (see above). The other version is devoid of the rear neck strap.</Notes>
</type>

<type> VM-40 (Volksgasmaske 40)
    <name>VM-40 (Volksgasmaske 40)</name>
    <Translation> People's Gas Mask 1940</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1940 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-013</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-013</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-013.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $25 </price>
    <Notes>  The German VM-40 is basically a cheaper replacement for the VM-37 that could be manufactured in larger quantities. The face piece was modified to incorporate head straps instead of the full "helmet" type design and the rubber quality was reduced in effort to save on cost as well. This was also a move to help conserve rubber, a much needed wartime material. The VM-40 was issued in a cardboard box and came in several sizes including a small version designed for young children.</Notes>
</type>

<type> VM-40 (Volksgasmaske 40) (Black version)
    <name>VM-40 (Volksgasmaske 40) (Black version)</name>
    <Translation> People's Gas Mask 1940</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1943 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-014</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-014</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-014.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $90 </price>
    <Notes>  This later black version of the VM-40 was again a result of depleted raw materials at Germany's disposal mid war. The black rubber versions were manufactured using a lesser quality rubber, and the head harness was also changed and made entirely from rubber as well.</Notes>
</type>

<type> M-44
    <name>M-44</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-015</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-015</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-015.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $85 </price>
    <Notes>  The M-44 was Germany's last effort to provide a civilian respirator to defend against Allied air raids. The M-44 was basically a cheapened down, simple mask made of a thin fabrisized rubber. Towards the end of the war, these masks were also issued with a cardboard filter as opposed to the alloy filter used with the VM-37 and VM-40 (see below).</Notes>
</type>

<type> M-44
    <name>M-44</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-016</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-016</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-016.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $85 </price>
    <Notes>  The M-44 was Germany's last effort to provide a civilian respirator to defend against Allied air raids. The M-44 was basically a cheapened down, simple mask made of a thin fabrisized rubber. Towards the end of the war, these masks were issued with a cardboard filter as opposed to the alloy filter used with the VM-37 and VM-40 (see above).</Notes>
</type>

<type> Gasbettchen (Small Gas Bed)
    <name>Gasbettchen </name>
    <Translation> Small Gas Bed</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s/1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-017</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-017</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-017.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $320</price>
    <Notes>  Along with the line of civilian gas masks, the Germans also designed several protective devices for small children and infants. The Gasbettchen was designed to fit a wide range of small children and babies that were not independently mobile yet. The device was basically a large fabric bag that was fitted over a wood frame. One side of the bag had an opening where the child could be inserted into the enclosure. The open end could then be "rolled-up" and clipped shut creating a gas-tight seal. A bellows attached to a long tube was then used by a caretaker to pump in filtered air, while the child could be observed via a large plastic window at the top. Expired air was pushed out through a one-way check valve above the plastic window.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Gasjäckchen (Gas Jacket)
    <name>Gasjäckchen</name>
    <Translation> Gas Jacket </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s/1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-018</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-018</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-018.jpg</pic>
    <price> $320</price>
    <Notes>  Like the Gasbettchen, the German Gasjäckchen was likewise an enclosure for small children attached to a bellows which pumped in "fresh" air. The Gasjäckchen however was designed for children old enough to walk around on their own. The Gasjäckchen was made to fit over the arms, head and torso of the child. The openings on the jacket were tied tightly around the wrists and waist to create a gas proof seal. Their was also a plastic visor and and exhale valve present similar to the ones used for the Gasbettchen.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Pferdegasmaske 38
    <name>Pferdegasmaske 38</name>
    <Translation> Horse Gas Mask 38</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a </Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1938 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-019</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-019</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-019.jpg</pic>
    <price> $400</price>
    <Notes>  The Pferdegasmaske 38 is one of two standard horse gas masks used by the Third Reich during WWII. The mask was designed to fit over the horses muzzle, and filter inhaled air via two circular filter cartridges. The Pferdegasmaske 38 is quite possibly the most common horse gas mask found on the collector's market, and when found is typically in good condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Stoltzenberg Vollblick Maske
    <name>Stoltzenberg Vollblick Maske</name>
    <Translation>Stoltzenberg full view mask </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-020</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-020</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-020.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $150</price>
    <Notes>  During the 1930s, several gas masks manufactured by Stoltzenberg were designed. Typically, they were made of canvas or fabric with a single large plastic eye shield offering a wide field of view.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Stoltzenberg Vollblick Maske
    <name>Stoltzenberg Vollblick Maske</name>
    <Translation>Stoltzenberg full view mask </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s/1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-021</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-021</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-021.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $20 </price>
    <Notes>  During the 1930s, several gas masks manufactured by Stoltzenberg were designed. Typically, they were made of canvas or fabric with a single large plastic eye shield offering a wide field of view.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Leder B-Maske
    <name>Leder B-Maske</name>
    <Translation>Leather B-mask </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Atemmaske(Breathing mask)</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-022</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-022</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-022.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $110</price>
    <Notes>  The Leder B-Maske was a mask primarily used for industrial applications. There were several different types of Leder-B masks designed for use in different environments.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Optische Gasmaske GM-44
    <name>Optische Gasmaske GM-44</name>
    <Translation>Optical Gas Mask GM-44 </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-023</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-023</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-023.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $150+</price>
    <Notes>  During WWII, most major countries involved designed masks for use with optical instruments. Germany was no exception. The Optische Gasmaske GM-44 was designed with two small, glass eye pieces that were attached to a threaded, intra- ocular adjustment rod very similar to the design used by the US Army for MI Optical Mask. This allowed the eye pieces to be positioned closer or farther apart, allowing for a customized fit to the wearer's eyes. Inside the mask behind the eye pieces were eye cups that also aided the wearer when using binoculars or other similar sighting devices.The mask also included a threaded microphone inlet, that could be capped off when not in use. The face piece was made entirely of leather, with a fabric and leather head harness. From the face piece in the chin area extended a long corrugated rubber breathing tube that was attached to a filter canister. The whole unit was carried in a green metal can. It might also be noted that a variant of this mask may have been carried aboard German submarines. The Optical GM-44 is quite scarce today but most surviving examples seem to be found in excellent co nditio n.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s/1940s </Date>
    <Frequency> Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-024</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-024</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-024.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $95 </price>
    <Notes>  This particular mask was most likely used for fire-fighting or industrial protection. The mask is made of a thin fabrisized rubber and used an elastic head harness for suspension.</Notes>
</type>

<type> GM-54
    <name>GM-54</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1954 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common/Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-025</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-025</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-025.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $45 </price>
    <Notes>  The GM-54 is really just a post war update to the GM-38. The mask's structure continued to use the same overall design with a rubberized face piece and a cylindrical filter in the snout position. The GM-54 was also carried in a metal tube.</Notes>
</type>

<type> GM-54
    <name>GM-54</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1954 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common/Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany</Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-026</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-026</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-026.jpg</pic>
    <price> $50</price>
    <Notes>  The GM-54 is really just a post war update to the GM-38. The mask's structure continued to use the same overall design with a rubberized face piece and a cylindrical filter in the snout position. The GM-54 was also carried in a metal tube. This version is the same as the above version but was issued with an updated filter.</Notes>
</type>

<type> GM-54 (Heavy weight version)
    <name>GM-54 (Heavy weight version)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1954 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-027</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-027</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-027.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $125</price>
    <Notes>  The GM-54 is really just a post war update to the GM-38. The mask's structure continued to use the same overall design with a rubberized face piece and a cylindrical filter in the snout position. The GM-54 was also carried in a metal tube. This version is the same as the above version but was issued with a long corrugated breathing tube and was most likely used by tank drivers or other vehicle crew members.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Z-56 (Zivilschutzmaske 56)
    <name>Z-56 (Zivilschutzmaske 56)</name>
    <Translation>Civil Defense Mask 56</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1956 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-028</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-028</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-028.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $35</price>
    <Notes>  The German Z56 is a post war civilian defense mask that was made entirely from white rubber. This was probably done to make civilians stand out from the military. The Z56 is quite common today and can still be found in un-issued original co nditio n.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Gasmaske 200
    <name>Gasmaske 200</name>
    <Translation> Gas Mask 200</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian/Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-029</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-029</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-029.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $65 </price>
    <Notes>  The Gasmaske 200 is an early German respirator most likely made to protect against industrial hazards. It was made of a fabrisized rubber with a small exhale valve on the left side.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1950s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-030</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-030</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-030.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $65 </price>
    <Notes>  This unknown mask is another early German mask most likely used for industrial purposes. The face piece is made of rubber with a small exhale valve on the left side.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   Cloetta Maske</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-031</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-031</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-031.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $100+</price>
    <Notes>  The mask pictured to the right is most likely another civilian grade mask made for use against fumes, smoke and other industrial hazards. However, this masks exact type and purpose is unknown.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Clora-Gasschutzmaske Modell 31
    <name>Clora-Gasschutzmaske Modell 31</name>
    <Translation>Clora gas protective mask model 31 </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1931 </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-039</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-039</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-039.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $55 </price>
    <Notes>  The Clora-Gasschutzmaske Modell 31 is an early mask most likely used for industrial applications. The mask was most likely originally equipped with a special purpose filter.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Vollmaske 747
    <name>Vollmaske 747</name>
    <Translation> Peoples Mask 747</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1930s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-047</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-047</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-047.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $35 </price>
    <Notes>  The Vollmaske 747 is just one of several different types of Vollmaske produced in Germany for civilian and industrial protection. This mask was most likely originally issued with a special purpose filter canister.</Notes>
</type>

<type> ASM (Atem Schutz Maske)
    <name>ASM (Atem Schutz Maske)</name>
    <Translation>Respirator </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany</Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-036</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-036</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-036.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $25 </price>
    <Notes>  The ASM mask was used as a civil defense mask by the DDR during the Cold War era. There were several types of ASM gas mask manufactured, and they all came equipped with a red painted filter (missing in photo to the right).</Notes>
</type>

<type> OXY-SR 30M
    <name>OXY-SR 30M</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1970s </Date>
    <Frequency> Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-048</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-048</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-048.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $300+</price>
    <Notes>  The OXY-SR 30M was manufactured by Dräger for use as a self-contained rebreather. The unit was most likely used for escape purposes, as the rebreather unit was quite small and most likely did not offer a long duration of breathing time.</Notes>
</type>

<type> ASM 13114
    <name>ASM 13114</name>
    <Translation> Respirator 13114</Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1944 </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-032</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-032</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-032.jpg</pic>
    <price>  $35 </price>
    <Notes>  This modern German mask features a single clear visor offering a wide field of view with an inner oro-nasal cup to reduce fogging. This mask is most likely a police or military mask.</Notes>
</type>

<type> M62
    <name>M62</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1962 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-033</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-033</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-033.jpg</pic>
    <price>? $75+</price>
    <Notes>  The M62 was basically an updated version of the GM-54. It was a standard rubber mask with a filter mount in the chin position. The mask was later updated and designated the M65.</Notes>
</type>

<type> M65
    <name>M65</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1965 </Date>
    <Frequency> Common</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-034</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-034</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-034.jpg</pic>
    <price> $159</price>
    <Notes>  The M65 is basically just an updated version of the M62. There were several versions of the M65 made including a version for civilians designated the M65Z. A later update of the M65 also incorporated a drinking device.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Karetta Maske
    <name>Karetta Maske</name>
    <Translation>Karetta Mask </Translation>
    <Aliases>   n/a</Aliases>
    <Date>   c. 1960s </Date>
    <Frequency> Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>  Germany </Country>
    <Function>  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence> GE-035</Refrence>
    <Ref>GE-035</Ref>
    <pic>https://rivethead13.github.io/Images/GE-035.jpg</pic>
    <price> $70</price>
    <Notes>  The Karetta Maske is very similar in design to the M65 except it was made from black rubber instead of the olive drab color used with the M65. Also like the M65, a later version of the Karetta Maske integrated a drinking device.</Notes>
</type>     
        </masks>