<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><masks><type> countriesBelgium
        <name>__________Belgium___________________________ </name>
        <Translation>___________Kingdom of Belgium___________________________</Translation>
        <Aliases> Aiases: n/a</Aliases>
        <Date> Date for Masks: 1918 - 1990s </Date>
        <Frequency> Frequency: Rare </Frequency>
        <Country>Capital: Brussles </Country>
        <Function>Use: Military/Civilian/Industrial </Function>
        <Refrence>Refrence: BE-???</Refrence>
        <Ref> Be </Ref>
        <pic>../Images/flagBelgium.jpg</pic>
        <price>Currency: Euro</price>
        <Notes>Notes:  Germany invaded Belgium in 1914 as part of the Schlieffen Plan and much of the Western Front fighting of World War I occurred in western parts of the country. The opening months of the war were known as the Rape of Belgium due to German atrocities. Belgium took over the German colonies of Ruanda-Urundi during the war, and they were mandated to Belgium in 1924 by the League of Nations. In the aftermath of the First World War, the Prussian districts of Eupen and Malmedy were annexed by Belgium in 1925, thereby causing the presence of a German-speaking minority. The country was again invaded by Germany in 1940 and was occupied until its liberation by the Allies in 1944. After World War II, a general strike forced king Leopold III, who many saw as collaborating with the Germans during the war, to abdicate in 1951.</Notes>
        </type>
        
<type> M-18
    <name>M-18</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1918</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-001</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-001</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-001.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $180</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  During WWI, captured German Lederschutzmasken were converted for use in Belgium using French ARS type filters. The mask is otherwise the same as the common German Lederschutzmaske in appearance. The masks were carried in a metal canister as well, like the German mask. Belgian M18s are somewhat difficult to find today, and they are often mistaken for regular German Lederschutzmasken.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Pirelli M29
    <name>Pirelli M29</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1929</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-002</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-002</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-002.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price: $400    </price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This early mask was used in Belgian and made by the Italian firm Pirelli. The face piece was made of dark leather, stitched together into a face form. A large and heavy filter canister was used with this mask, which was connected via a long corrugated tube. The breathing tube was attached to an angled metal pipe fitted into the the mask's face piece. </Notes>
</type>

<type> Sacic Gas Mask
    <name>Sacic Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country: Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use: Civilian/Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-003</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-003</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-003.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $100</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Sacic Gas Mask is one of the more common WWII Belgian gas masks that can still be found today in excellent condition. The mask used an all rubber face piece and glass eye pieces. There are at least two different versions of the Sacic Mask, one with smaller eye pieces and one with slightly larger eye pieces (see below). Both versions also used different filter canisters, but were carried in similar canvas bags.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Sacic Gas Mask
    <name>Sacic Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian/Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-004</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-004</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-004.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $100</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Sacic Gas Mask is one of the more common WWII Belgian gas masks that can still be found today in excellent condition. The mask used an all rubber face piece and glass eye pieces. There are at least two different versions of the Sacic Mask, one with smaller eye pieces (see above) and one with slightly larger eye pieces. Both versions also used different filter canisters, but were carried in similar canvas bags.</Notes>
</type>

<type> B.B. Gas Mask
    <name>B.B. Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian/Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-017</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-017</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-017.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $115</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The B.B. Gas Mask is an earlier variant of the more commonly found Sacic gas mask (above). The overall appearance is basically the same, however this mask came with an early type filter. The carrier was also very similar to the other Belgian Sacic type masks.</Notes>
</type>

<type> S.A. Gas Mask
    <name>S.A. Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country: Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use: Civilian/Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-016</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-016</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-016.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $100*</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Belgian S.A. gas mask is very similar to the Sacic Gas Mask but was made from light khaki rubber and used a smaller filter. The carrier was also different.</Notes>
</type>

<type> AG.15
    <name>AG.15</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. late 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian/Civil Defense</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-005</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-005</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-005.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $115</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The AG.15 is another of the imported masks used in Belgium during the WWII era. The mask used a design similar to the earlier Sacic masks but was equipped with a smaller filter canister and a different outlet valve. The AG.15 is somewhat rare today but when found is usually in good condition. The example pictured to the right was used by Civil Defense personnel while another version without the breathing hose was issued to civilians.</Notes>
</type>

<type> AG.9
    <name>AG.9</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. late 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-006</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-006</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-006.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $75
</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Belgian AG.9 is a simple civilian mask cut from a single sheet of rubber with 2 head straps used for suspension. An exhale valve is present on the front of the mask above the filter inlet. The AG.9 is somewhat common, and when found is usually in good condition, complete with its cylindrical metal carrier.</Notes>
</type>

<type> S.B.A. (Societé Belge d'Azote) Gas Mask
    <name>S.B.A. (Societé Belge d'Azote) Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> S.B.A. (Belgian Society of Nitrogen) Gas Mask</Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases: n/a </Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s/early 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian/Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-007</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-007</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-007.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $155</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This Belgian mask, made by the Societé Belge d'Azote (Belgian Society of Nitrogen) is quite rare. There are at least three or four different variations of this mask, some with a filter directly attached and some with a large filter and breathing tube (see below). There are also some early versions made from gray rubber instead of the more common brown rubber. Some versions have metal head harness connectors and some have plastic parts. Most likely this mask was used by civilians for industrial purposes, but it may have also been used for other civilian applications. It was later replaced by the common L.702.</Notes>
</type>

<type> S.B.A. (Societé Belge d'Azote) Gas Mask
    <name>S.B.A. (Societé Belge d'Azote) Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> S.B.A. (Belgian Society of Nitrogen) gas mask</Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  S.B.A. (Societé Belge d'Azote) Gas Mask</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s/early 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian/Industrial</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-008</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-008</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-008.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  SOLD</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This Belgian mask, made by the Societé Belge d'Azote (Belgian Society of Nitrogen) is quite rare. There are at least three or four different variations of this mask, some with a filter directly attached (see above) and some with a large filter and breathing tube. There are also some early versions made from gray rubber instead of the more common brown rubber. Some versions have metal head harness connectors and some have plastic parts. Most likely this mask was used by civilians for industrial purposes, but it may have also been used for other civilian applications. It was later replaced by the common L.702.</Notes>
</type>

<type> L.702
    <name>L.702</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Common</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-009</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-009</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-009.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price: $35</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Belgian L.702 is quite possibly the most commonly found Belgian gas mask from WWII. The mask was carried in a tall metal carrier, with "L.702" stamped on the lid for easy identification. There were several versions of this mask made between the 1930s and 1950s, with the type pictured at right being the most common. One version of this mask designated the L.702 "Typ Activ" was used by Civil Defense and Air Raid teams. There were also several versions exported to other European countries which varied slightly in design and parts.</Notes>
</type>

<type> L.702 (40mm export version)
    <name>L.702 (40mm export version)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Holland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-010</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-010</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-010.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $85
</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This later version of the Belgian L.702 is slightly more rare than its earlier and more common counterpart (see above). This version differs in that it used a 40mm filter canister instead of the earlier 25mm canister. This version was designed as an export model that was mostly used in Holland.</Notes>
</type>

<type> L.702 (aluminum inlet export version)
    <name>L.702 (aluminum inlet export version)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium/France</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-015</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-015</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-015.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $125</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This version of the Belgian L.702 was manufactured with an aluminum filter inlet assembly designed to accommodate large threaded (42mm) French filter canisters. The face piece of the mask was also assembled a little differently than the standard Belgian version.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Englebert E.V. 639
    <name>Englebert E.V. 639</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-011</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-011</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-011.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $100</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Englebert E.V. 639 is a WWII era Belgian mask designed for use by young children, as the mask and filter are both quite small. The unit was carried in a small metal canister that could be easily slung by younger civilians. The E.V. 639 was manufactured in at least three different sizes to accommodate various age groups and head sizes.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Englebert E2
    <name>Englebert E2</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s/1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-012</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-012</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-012.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $100</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Englebert E2 is another of the many civilian respirators used during the WWII era in Belgium. Like the Englebert E.V. 639, the E2 was made of black rubber, and used a similar filter canister. The mask was carried in a gray metal canister and can still be found today in excellent complete condition.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Englebert E2
    <name>Englebert E2</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s/1940s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-013</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-013</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-013.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price: $180</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This rare version of the E2 came with a large white filter canister and was carried in a green canvas bag. The large filter canister appears to have been used for civil defense, but it is unclear what the filter is designed for. Otherwise, this version is identical to the above more common version.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Englebert EV 639 
    <name>Englebert EV 639 </name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civil Defense</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-018</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-018</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-018.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $50 </price>
    <Notes>Notes:  Very simple and thin mask made by Englebert Änliche. The RS38, only has
3-point harness and 25 mm standard thread for the passive civil defense.</Notes>
</type>

<type> BEM 4 GP
    <name>BEM 4 GP</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1990s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Uncommon/Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Belgium</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: BE-014</Refrence>
    <Ref>BE-014</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/BE-014.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price: $249</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This modern style Belgian respirator is quite possibly one of the best currently used designs in Europe. The mask features a wide field of view and an adjustable filter inlet. This feature enables the wearer to position the filter canister on either side of the face piece, or below the chin (see details) without removing the filter or changing out other parts (such as a voice-mitter). The BEM 4 GP is also quite comfortable and can be worn for extended periods of time. The mask is carried in a tall, tactical fabric bag. BEM 4 GP masks are now becoming available on the surplus market and are usually in mint, un-issued condition.</Notes>
</type>             </masks>