<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><masks><type> countriesFinland
        <name>_________Finland___________________________ </name>
        <Translation>_________Republic of Finland___________________________</Translation>
        <Aliases> Aiases: n/a</Aliases>
        <Date> Date for Masks: 1930s - 1990s </Date>
        <Frequency> Frequency: Rare </Frequency>
        <Country>Capital: Helsinki </Country>
        <Function>Use: Military/Civilian/Industrial </Function>
        <Refrence>Refrence: FI-???</Refrence>
        <Ref> FI </Ref>
        <pic>../Images/flagFinland.jpg</pic>
        <price>Currency: Euro</price>
        <Notes>Notes: During World War II, Finland fought the Soviet Union twice: in the Winter War of 1939–40 after the Soviet Union had attacked Finland; and in the Continuation War of 1941–44, following Operation Barbarossa, in which Germany invaded the Soviet Union. For 872 days, German and Finnish armies besieged Leningrad, the Soviet Union's second largest city. The siege of Leningrad resulted in the deaths of some one million of the city's inhabitants. After fighting a major Soviet offensive in June/July 1944 to a standstill, Finland reached an armistice with the Soviet Union. This was followed by the Lapland War of 1944–45, when Finland forced the Germans out of northern Finland.

The treaties signed in 1947 and 1948 with the Soviet Union included Finnish obligations, restraints and reparations – as well as further Finnish territorial concessions begun in the Moscow Peace Treaty of 1940. As a result of the two wars, Finland was forced to cede most of Finnish Karelia, Salla and Petsamo, which amounted to ten percent of its land area and twenty percent of its industrial capacity, including the ports of Vyborg  and ice-free Liinakhamari . Almost the whole population, some 400,000 persons, fled these areas. Finland was never occupied by Soviet forces and retained its independence, however at a loss of about 93 000 soldiers killed, by proportion the third-highest loss rate in World War II. </Notes>
    </type>
    

<type> m/30
    <name>m/30</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Finland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: FI-001</Refrence>
    <Ref>FI-001</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/FI-001.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:? $50+</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This unique mask was used by the Finnish military throughout WWII. The masks face piece was made from an orange rubber coated with a drab colored stockinet material. A large filter canister was used and attached via a medium length corrugated breathing tube. An exhale valve is present under the chin.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Finland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: FI-002</Refrence>
    <Ref>FI-002</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/FI-002.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $90
</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This simple civilian mask was issued in Finland in large quantities during WWII. The mask was made of a thick orange rubber coated with a drab colored stockinet material like the m/30. This mask was typically issued in a tall metal can for easy carrying and removal.</Notes>
</type>

<type> m/38
    <name>m/38</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1938</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Finland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: FI-003</Refrence>
    <Ref>FI-003</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/FI-003.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $125</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Finnish m/38 is very similar to the German GM-38 and was issued throughout the WWII era in several versions. The version pictured at right used metal parts for the inlet/outlet assembly while some versions used Bakelite parts (see below). The m/38 was issued in a tall fabric carrier.</Notes>
</type>

<type> m/38
    <name>m/38</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1938</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Finland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military/Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: FI-004</Refrence>
    <Ref>FI-004</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/FI-004.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $125</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This version of the m/38 used Bakelite parts as opposed to metal parts for the inlet/outlet assembly. These differences could reflect different material shortages that occurred during the war. It was also possibly a design enhancement aimed at making the mask lighter.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Unknown
    <name>Unknown</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare/Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Finland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian/Industrial?</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: FI-005</Refrence>
    <Ref>FI-005</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/FI-005.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:? $100+</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This WWII era Finnish mask was most likely used for civilian protection, being that it has a bright orange face piece. However, this mask may be a special purpose mask used to protect against industrial hazards.</Notes>
</type>

<type> m/39
    <name>m/39</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1939</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Finland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Civilian</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: FI-006</Refrence>
    <Ref>FI-006</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/FI-006.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $115</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This Finnish civilian mask closely resembles the German VM37, which also used a "helmet" type face piece that encapsulated the wearer's entire face and most of the head. The m/39 can still be found today in its original cardboard carton.</Notes>
</type>

<type> Horse Gas Mask
    <name>Horse Gas Mask</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1930s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Scarce</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Finland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: FI-014</Refrence>
    <Ref>FI-014</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/FI-014.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price: Museum Piece</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  (The Picture in below is not confirmed as this mask.) The Finnish Horse Gas Mask is a very rare WWII era animal respirator designed to be used by the mounted calvary. The mask was equipped with an over sized filter canister that was slung during use in a khaki canvas bag. The mask's nose piece was made of leather and several layers of fabric padding.</Notes>
</type>

<type> m/61 (1st model)
    <name>m/61 (1st model)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1960s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Finland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: FI-007</Refrence>
    <Ref>FI-007</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/FI-007.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $115</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Finnish m/61 is a licensed copy of the US M9 design. The earliest type of m/61 is virtually identical to its US counterpart, but later versions used different exhale valves. The last version of the m/61 was updated with a combination speech diaphragm and outlet valve assembly made from hard molded plastic (see below).</Notes>
</type>

<type> m/61 (2nd model)
    <name>m/61 (2nd model)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1960s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Finland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: FI-008</Refrence>
    <Ref>FI-008</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/FI-008.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $80</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The Finnish m/61 is a licensed copy of the US M9 design. This version of the m/61 used a slightly different exhale valve compared to the above version and was later updated again with a combination speech diaphragm and outlet valve assembly made from hard molded plastic (see below).</Notes>
</type>

<type> m/61 (3rd model)
    <name>m/61 (3rd model)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1960s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Finland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: FI-009</Refrence>
    <Ref>FI-009</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/FI-009.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $90</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  This version of the m/61 was last model produced, and it featured an updated speech diaphragm and outlet valve assembly that gives it a distinct appearance that sets it apart from the previous versions. Despite the changes to the outlet assembly, the m/61's main structure remained basically the same until it was replaced by the m/95 in the 1990s.</Notes>
</type>

<type> m/95
    <name>m/95</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1990s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Uncommon</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Finland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: FI-010</Refrence>
    <Ref>FI-010</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/FI-010.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price: $200</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  During the 1990s, Kemira Safety of Finland (now Scott Safety) developed a superb NBC protective mask designated the m/95. This modern NBC respirator incorporated a drinking device and the ability to use corrective lenses inside the mask. The filter could be attached to either the left side or the right side of the face piece by switching a detachable voice-mitter with the filter. The mask also used a modern styled head-net for suspension to enhance comfort and fit. The m/95 was manufactured in one universal size for general use, however a small size was also made (see below).</Notes>
</type>

<type> m/95 (size small)
    <name>m/95 (size small)</name>
    <Translation> </Translation>
    <Aliases> Aliases:  n/a</Aliases>
    <Date> Date:  c. 1990s</Date>
    <Frequency> Frequency:  Rare</Frequency>
    <Country>Country:  Finland</Country>
    <Function>Use:  Military</Function>
    <Refrence>Refrence: FI-011</Refrence>
    <Ref>FI-011</Ref>
    <pic>../Images/FI-011.jpg</pic>
    <price>Price:  $125</price>
    <Notes>Notes:  The m/95 pictured at right is identical to the regular m/95 but was made in a small size to accommodate smaller heads. It is also worth noting that the m/95 was later produced and issued without the exhale valve deflector (a round cup that fit over the exhale valve to force expired air away from the mask - see above). This accessory was found to be unnecessary and omitted from further production.</Notes>
</type>             </masks>